<Module xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1" xmlns:sec="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1/section" xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" boilerplate="yes" target-product="Enterprise Session Controller" name="Enterprise Session Controller">


  <!-- PPReference (all documents) -->
  <PPReference>
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPVersion>1.1</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2025-03-28</PPPubDate>
      <Keywords>QQQQ</Keywords>               <!-- This field is unused and optional -->
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>

<!-- Revision History (all documents) -->
  <RevisionHistory>
    <entry>
      <version>Round 1</version>
      <date>2015-04-23</date>
      <subject>First draft of version 1.0 for comment</subject>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date>2015-08-14</date>
      <subject>Release - first version released</subject>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <version>2.0</version>
      <date>2024-03-28</date>
      <subject>Updated for CC:2022, or whatever</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>

<release-notes><h:h3>TDs Applied</h:h3></release-notes><!-- Included Packages (all documents) (optional) -->
<!-- One entry for each package -->
    <include-pkg id="tls">
      <git>
	    <url>https://github.com/commoncriteria/tls</url>  <!-- url of github repo -->
	    <branch>release-1.1</branch>                      <!-- github branch of published version -->
      </git>
      <url>https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=439&amp;id=439</url>  <!-- url of published document on NIAP site -->
      <depends on="pizza"/>     <!-- If package inclusion is dependent on something. Absent if package inclusion is mandatory -->
	</include-pkg>
	    
	<include-pkg id="ssh">
	  <git>
	    <url>https://github.com/commoncriteria/ssh</url>
	    <branch>release-1.0</branch>
	  </git>
	  <url>https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=389&amp;id=389</url>
   </include-pkg>	

<!-- Modules (optional). A properly constructed PP does not need this section. -->
<!-- It is abomination that PPs refer to Modules. This should never happen. -->
<!-- But this is how it is done. But don't do it.  -->
<!--
   <modules required="yes">
      <module id="client-virt">
		<git>
			<url>https://github.com/commoncriteria/clientvirtualization</url>
			<branch>master</branch>
		</git>
        <url>https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=409&amp;id=409</url> 
	  </module>
      <module id="server-virt">
		<git>
			<url>https://github.com/commoncriteria/servervirtualization</url>
			<branch>master</branch>
		</git>
		<url>https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=410&amp;id=410</url>
	  </module>
   </modules>
-->

<!-- PP Preferences (all documents) -->
<pp-preferences>
     <!-- Indicate that audit events are defined with their SFRs -->
	 <!-- All new documents should do it this way. This will become the default, if it hasn't already.  -->
	 <!-- And this preference might not even be necessary. I should test it. -->
     <audit-events-in-sfrs/>         
	 
	 <!-- Indicates that audit events will be displayed along the associated SFR in the published document -->
	 <!-- rather than in an audit table. -->
<!--     <display-audit-with-sfrs/>     -->

	 <!-- Indicates that the document is using CC:2022. -->
	 <!-- This setting has already been deprecated, but is still allowed for backward compatiblity -->
	 <!-- New douments shoudl use the <CClaimsInfo> element to specify CC:2022 --> 
     <using-cc2022/>     
  </pp-preferences>


  <!-- Introduction (all documents) -->
  <section title="Introduction" id="sec-intro">

    <!-- PP or TOE Overview -->

    <section title="PP Overview" id="sec-ppoverview">
		<h:p>The scope of this PP-Module is to describe the security functionality of an Enterprise Session Controller
		(ESC) in terms of [CC] and to define functional and assurance requirements for such products. This PPModule is intended for use with the following Base-PPs:
		</h:p>
		<h:ul><h:li>collaborative Protection Profile for Network Devices (NDcPP), Version 3.0e
		</h:li></h:ul>
		<h:p>This Base-PP is valid because a device that implements an ESC is a specific type of network device, and
		there is nothing about the implementation of an ESC that would prevent any of the security capabilities
		defined by the Base-PP from being satisfied. This PP-Module does not mandate a particular architecture;
		the TOE may be either standalone or distributed as permitted by the Base-PP.</h:p>

		<!-- ...the PP overview briefly describes the usage of the TOE and its major security features,
    	identifies the TOE type, and identifies any major non-TOE hardware/software/firmware available
		to the TOE.
		-->   

	</section>  <!-- PP Overview -->
	
	<!-- CC and Tech terms.  -->
	<!-- CC terms are auto-generated -->
	<!-- All tech terms are generated from the list below. -->
	<!-- You should add and delete tech terms as required by the technology type. -->
	<tech-terms>
	  <!-- To remove an irrlevant CC term from the document, use the <suppress> element -->
      <suppress>Distributed TOE</suppress>   


      <term full="Audit Log">
		A persistent record of security-relevant events such as administrative access,
		administrative actions performed, system failures, and the establishment and
		termination of remote communications.
      </term>
	  <term full="Call Detail Record">A log of call metadata that can be used to determine characteristics of a call, such as
		its length and involved parties, without recording any of its content.</term>
      <term full="Call Processing">The act of translating a dialed phone number into an attempt to establish a
connection with the appropriate party; this is in contrast to the actual transmission of
voice/video media over a call.</term>
	  <term full="Enterprise Session Controller">A type of network device that is responsible for establishment, processing, and termination of Voice/Video over IP (VVoIP) calls.</term>
	  <term full="Service Provider">A third-party telecommunications company that is responsible for providing
commercial service and connectivity to the worldwide telephone network.
</term>
	  <term full="Session Border Controller">A type of network device that resides on the edge of a VVoIP network that is
		responsible for filtering corrupted or potentially malicious traffic and preventing it
		from entering or leaving the network.</term>
	  <term full="System Log">A live display of system characteristics that can be viewed on demand to diagnose
system performance in real-time. This data is typically only stored for a short period
of time if at all.</term>
	  <term full="Telecommunications Device">In this PP-Module, used to refer generally to any piece of infrastructure equipment
		that the ESC may connect to other than a VVoIP Endpoint, which could include
		equipment such as a call conferencing server or Session Border Controller.
		</term>
		<term full="Trunking">The concept of connecting multiple networks together; analogous to the use of a T1 line in a legacy telephone network.</term>
		<term full="VVoIP Endpoint">A VVoIP-capable phone or software application that a human user can use to make or receive a voice or video call.</term>
	  <term full="Call Detail Record" abbr="CDR"/>
	  <term full="Enterprise Session Controller" abbr="ESC"/>
	  <term full="Internet Protocol Private Branch Exchange" abbr="IP-PBX"/>
	  <term full="Media Gateway Control Protocol" abbr="MGCP"/>
	  <term full="Collaborative Protection Profile for Network Devices" abbr="NDcPP"/>
	  <term full="Operations, Administration, and Management" abbr="OA&amp;M"/>
	  <term full="Organizational Security Policies" abbr="OSP"/>
	  <term full="Session Border Controller" abbr="SBC"/>
	  <term full="Session Initiation Protocol" abbr="SIP"/>
	  <term full="Voice/Video over IP" abbr="VVoIP"/>

    </tech-terms>    

	<!-- Other sections can be added here. -->
	<!-- Commen examples include Scope of Document, Intended Audiance, Compliant Targets of Evaluation,
	     TOE Boundary, TOE Operational Environment, and Roles. These sections can also be included in the
		 TOE/PP Overview aove. -->
    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="sec-TOEdescription">
	<h:p>The Target of Evaluation (TOE) that is defined by the combination of the NDcPP and this PP-Module is a
network device, either a dedicated appliance with a non-modifiable operating system, or a general-purpose server running an independent commercially-available operating system that provides ESC
functionality. Regardless of whether the TOE is a standalone appliance or a general-purpose server that is
configured to function as an ESC, the TOE must be capable of satisfying all of the mandatory requirements
of the NDcPP.</h:p><h:p>An ESC is a privately-owned telecommunication switch where its primary function is to set up, process,
and terminate voice and video calls over an enterprise-wide Internet Protocol (IP) network. ESC operation
is analogous to the tasks of 1930’s telephone switchboard-operators, which is to patch (connect) together
callers to callees. But today’s ESC executes switchboard operations automatically, while providing
simultaneous connectivity to hundreds of callers virtually instantaneously. In addition to establishing,
processing, and managing thousands of connected calls, most ESCs support auxiliary services such as
VVoIP Conferencing, Voicemail, Chat, Telepresence, Encrypted Communications, and Protocol Translation
for end-to-end connectivity of diverse endpoints.</h:p><h:p>ESCs are commonly known as Call Servers, Communications Servers, and Call-Processing Systems, and
they vary in complexities and capabilities. The typical ESC can manage thousands of calls between diverse
client devices such as VoIP-handsets, Softphones, Desktop Telepresence Systems, Room-size Video
Telepresence Systems, and Mobile Devices. ESCs are normally installed within a SCIF or other entry-controlled environment, especially systems that can register numerous VVoIP endpoints. To protect the
ESC, a Session Border Controller (SBC) is installed on the outer edge of the VVoIP network to help protect
the ESC from external network attacks. Also note that a fairly robust ESC system includes many major
components such as its own database, operating system (O/S), conferencing system, dial plan, network
manager, call-signaling protocols (e.g. H.323, Session Initiation Protocol (SIP), SS7), and its own
‘Operations, Administration, and Management (OA&amp;M)’ application system.</h:p><h:p>If any one of these major components is successfully attacked, then one can expect the entire ESC system
to be negatively impacted. The intention of this PP-Module is to provide a list of security requirements
needed by an ESC for protection of its functionality and protection of the VVoIP communications it is
responsible for facilitating.</h:p>
		</section>
      <sec:TOE_Boundary>
	  <h:p>An ESC is a logical component of a physical hardware appliance that is responsible for establishing
connectivity between VVoIP endpoints. The ESC is an advanced version of a legacy IP-PBX system. As a
specific type of network device, an ESC TOE will be evaluated against both the NDcPP and this PP-Module.
All functionality described by the SFRs are within the TOE boundary, as is the ability for the TSF to establish
secure remote connections with trusted entities in the OE.</h:p><h:p>Figure 1 below shows a typical VVoIP infrastructure in which an ESC is deployed.</h:p>
        <figure entity="images/network_diagram.png" title="Representative ESC Deployment" id="toe"/>
		<h:p>As can be seen from this figure, the ESC’s purpose is to provide an interface between VVoIP networks in order
		to connect calls. The ESC depends on or communicates with a number of services that are located within the
		internal network such as voicemail, conferencing, Network Time Protocol (NTP), Domain Name System, and
		software updates that are downloaded from VVoIP endpoint manufacturers and stored on the ESC for
		distribution to the clients.</h:p><h:p>Certain storage capabilities may be implemented exclusively within the TOE or within both the TOE and its OE (such as the TOE maintaining an internal audit log that is also written to an external audit server).</h:p><h:p>For connecting networks, the ESC relies on edge routing to handle lower-level communications between
		the networks and on a SBC to filter out potentially malicious activity.</h:p><h:p>The ESC itself, which can be administered locally or remotely, consists of several different logical
		components, as shown in Figure 2 below.</h:p>
		<figure entity="images/components_diagram.png" title="ESC Components" id="c-toe"/>
		<h:p>As can be seen from the figure above, the ESC provides the following logical capabilities:</h:p><h:ul>
		<h:li>OA&amp;M – Responsible for providing a management interface to the ESC’s configuration.</h:li>
		<h:li>Call Processing – Responsible for setting up and tearing down calls between VVoIP endpoints using
		one or more call control protocols.</h:li>
		<h:li>Call Detail Records – Responsible for storage of call activity for auditing purposes.</h:li>
		<h:li>Voice/Video Media Conferencing, Controls, and Storage – responsible for establishing multi-way
		conference calls and storage of call recordings.</h:li>
		</h:ul>Different ESCs may implement these capabilities in different ways. This PP-Module defines a minimum
baseline of capabilities that all conformant ESCs must provide.
      </sec:TOE_Boundary>

	  <sec:Use_Cases>
	  <h:p>Requirements in this PP-Module are designed to address the security problem in the following use cases.
		Use cases are not mutually exclusive; a TOE may implement more than one of these use cases. The
		description of these use cases provide instructions for how the TOE and its OE should be made to support
		the functionality required by this PP-Module.
		</h:p><h:p>This PP-Module defines four potential use cases for the ESC TOE:</h:p>
	  
	   <usecases>
        <usecase id="usecase1" title="Dedicated Appliance">
          <description>The ESC is sold and packaged as a standalone network appliance that does not have a direct interface to the underlying platform operating system, customized application, or commercial off-the-shelf database.</description>
        </usecase>
		<usecase id="usecase2" title="Call Processing (Connect VVoIP Calls Together)">
          <description>The ESC serves as a call control system that employs multiple technologies for processing and
			managing voice/video calls between end-point devices. The ESC receives a call-request message
			from the source IP-phone (endpoint-A) and then locates and connects the call-originator to the
			destination device (endpoint-B). The ESC is used as a centralized system to process, manage, and
			connect calls between registered IP-phones. It should be noted that H.323 and SIP are the ESC’s
			most commonly used call-processing (i.e. call control) protocols. Both H.323 and SIP are used to
			set up, process, and terminate voice/video calls between endpoints. Supplemental call control
			protocols such as Media Gateway Control Protocol (MGCP) and SS7 do not limit ESC capabilities,
			but instead enhances its functionality. Both H.323 and SIP provide an ESC with the capabilities
			required for execution of all use cases. Both H.323 and SIP provide the ESC with call control
			capabilities, support trunking between the ESC and Service Providers, support trunking between
			an array of ESCs, and can use encryption schemes that secure the ESC’s call control functions.
					</description>
        </usecase>
		<usecase id="usecase3" title="Trunk Calls to/from Telecommunications Service Provider">
          <description>The ESC may support the ability to bundle numerous calls that originate from locally-registered
			VVoIP devices onto an ESC’s communication trunk for connectivity through a telecommunications
			service provider (e.g. Verizon) to remote endpoints. In this case, the ESC supports the aggregation
			of traffic for all registered IP devices for the purpose of passing local calls over a single trunk to an
			external service provider. This allows for a simplified network deployment where a single
			connection from the ESC to the service provider can support a large number of devices, rather
			than requiring each individual device to connect to the service provider separately.
          </description>
        </usecase>
		<usecase id="usecase4" title="Trunk Calls in/out to Remote ESCs">
          <description>Similar to trunking calls to telecommunications service providers, the ESC can trunk a large volume
			of calls to other remote ESCs. An example of this deployment is a meshed configuration of trunk-connected ESCs that are deployed to support a metropolitan-sized enterprise-wide VVoIP call processing network. This particular type of use case may not require any of the meshed ESCs to
			be connected to a service provider.
          </description>
        </usecase>
	
		</usecases>
		</sec:Use_Cases>
		</section>
     <!-- Compliant TOEs -->
<section title="Conformance Claims" id="sec-cclaims">

	<!-- cc-version: cc-2022r1 or cc-31r5   -->
	<!-- cc-approach: standard or direct-rationale  -->
	<!-- display: Should this info be displayed in the Conformance -->
	<!-- Claims section? If no, you have to write a free-form section -->
	<CClaimsInfo cc-version="cc-2022r1" cc-approach="direct-rationale" display="yes">                 

		<!-- Conformance for STs: exact, strict, or demonstrable -->
		<cc-st-conf>exact</cc-st-conf>                  

		<!-- Part 2 & 3 conformance (extended or conformant) -->
		<cc-pt2-conf>extended</cc-pt2-conf>           
		<cc-pt3-conf>conformant</cc-pt3-conf>           

		<!-- Claims conformance to these other PPs (none)-->
		<cc-pp-conf/>              		  
		
		<!-- Can be in a configuration with these PPs and Modules -->
		<cc-pp-config-with/>

		<!-- Package claims -->
        
		<cc-pkg-claim/>

		

	</CClaimsInfo>
  </section>  



  <!-- Conformance Claims Section -->
  <!-- New conformance claims section for CC:2022. -->
  <!-- If boilerplate is "yes" something that is probably incorrect is generated -->
  
  

  
  <section title="Security Problem Definition" id="sec-spd">
  <h:p>The security problem is described in terms of the threats that the TOE is expected to address, assumptions
	about its operational environment, and any organizational security policies that the TOE is expected to
	enforce.</h:p>
	<h:p>The ESC is a network appliance that incorporates multiple components and protocols, and is designed
	with the purpose of connecting and managing calls that emanate from registered VVoIP endpoints. The
	ESC is also designed to provide centralized control of an enterprise-wide VVoIP communication network.
	As the central control system that manages and processes VVoIP calls from as many as 50,000 endpoints
	per node, it is critically important for the ESC to be protected because it is a single point of failure for tens
	of thousands of end-users.</h:p>
	<h:p>As a centralized system the ESC is subject to attacks from the VVoIP endpoints that are registered to the
	ESC. Any VVoIP endpoint could be a threat to launch a malicious attack against the ESC. Therefore the ESC
	shall possess the security requirements needed for mitigating such a threat type.
	</h:p>
	<h:p>Note that as PP-Module of the NDcPP, all threats, assumptions, and Organizational Security Policies (OSPs)
	defined there will also apply to an ESC TOE unless otherwise specified.
	</h:p>
	<h:p>The Security Functional Requirements (SFRs) defined in this PP-Module will mitigate the threats that are
	defined in the PP-Module but will also mitigate some NDcPP threats in more comprehensive detail due to
	the specific capabilities provided by an ESC.</h:p>


    <section title="Threats" id="sec-threats">
	The following threats defined in this PP-Module extend the threats defined by the Base-PP.
	
      <threats>
        <threat name="T.MALICIOUS_TRAFFIC" id="t-malicious-traffic">
		
          <description> A malformed packet is a protocol packet containing modified data not recognizable by the receiving
			device (e.g. TOE), or contains modified protocol packets intended to crash or cause the TOE to act in
			ways unintended. An attacker may attempt to use a VVoIP endpoint to send these malformed packets
			or malicious traffic towards the TOE in an attempt to control or crash the call control system and
			connected network devices. To mitigate VVoIP endpoint devices from being used to successfully
			launch malicious traffic, the TOE must provide encryption remedies to prevent modification of
			protocol packets. The TOE must also provide authentication mechanisms to prevent unauthorized
			VVoIP endpoints from improperly registering to the ESC for the purpose of launching malicious
			attacks.</description>
			<!--O.MEDIA_RECORDING-->
			<addressed-by>FCS_NTP_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to support NTP communications to obtain reliable time data that is used for accurate recording of call metadata.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FPT_STM_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to synchronize with an NTP server for reliable time data that is used for accurate recording of call metadata.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FAU_GEN.1/CDR</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to generate call detail records of VVoIP communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FAU_STG.2/CDR</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to securely store call detail records.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FAU_VVR_EXT.1</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by allowing the TOE to claim whether or not it performs voice/video recording of VVoIP communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FAU_STG.2/VVR (selection-based)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to securely store call detail records, if generated by the TSF.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FAU_VVR_EXT.2 (selection-based)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining when voice and video recordings are generated by the TSF, how they are stored, and how they are uniquely identified for future access.</rationale>
			<!--  O.SECURE_VVOIP-->
			<addressed-by>FCS_DTLSS_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the use of DTLS to protect transmitted voice/video media if this is the chosen method for securing it.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_DTLSS_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring any implementation of DTLS to use mutual authentication.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_NTP_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to support NTP communications to obtain reliable time data that is used for establishment of valid cryptographic channels.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSC_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSS_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSS_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.1/Rev (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring X.509 validation in support of establishing TLS communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring X.509 authentication in support of establishing TLS communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.3 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to be able to request an X.509 certificate that it can present to external entities when establishing cryptographic communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FPT_STM_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to synchronize with an NTP server for reliable time data that is used for establishment of valid cryptographic channels.</rationale><comment> this is a duplicate from O.SECURE_VVOIP and O.MEDIA_RECORDING</comment>
			<addressed-by>FDP_IFC.1</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining an enterprise session controller policy to broker VVoIP endpoint communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FDP_IFF.1</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining the rules enforced by the enterprise session controller policy.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_UAU.2/TC</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring authentication of telecommunications devices that are connected to the TOE before the TSF will interact with them.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_UAU.2/VVoIP</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring authentication of VVoIP endpoints that are connected to the TOE before the TSF will interact with them.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FTP_ITC.1/ESC</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining the trusted channels used for protection of signaling and media data used in VVoIP and SIP trunking communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FPT_TUD_EXT.1/VVoIP (implementation-dependent)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by optionally allowing the TOE to distribute software/firmware updates to connected VVoIP endpoints.</rationale>
			<!--O.SELF_PROTECTION-->
			<addressed-by>FAU_GEN.1/Log</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by generating real-time diagnostic activity for the TOE’s behavior that can be used to determine if it is experiencing conditions that could lead to a failure state.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FDP_RIP.1</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by ensuring the permanent erasure of residual data so that a decommissioned or refurbished device cannot be used to disclose TSF data without authorization.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FPT_FLS.1/ESC</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by ensuring that the TSF enters a secure failure state if specific hardware or software failures are detected.</rationale>
			</threat>
			<threat name="T.NETWORK_DISCLOSURE" id="t-network-disclosure"><description> An attacker may attempt to “map” IP addresses of VVoIP endpoint/devices and other
			telecommunications equipment for the purpose of determining the organizational structure of the
			enterprise, providing reconnaissance for future targeted attacks.</description>
			<!--O.SECURE_VVOIP,  -->
			<addressed-by>FCS_DTLSS_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the use of DTLS to protect transmitted voice/video media if this is the chosen method for securing it.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_DTLSS_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring any implementation of DTLS to use mutual authentication.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_NTP_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to support NTP communications to obtain reliable time data that is used for establishment of valid cryptographic channels.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSC_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSS_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSS_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.1/Rev (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring X.509 validation in support of establishing TLS communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring X.509 authentication in support of establishing TLS communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.3 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to be able to request an X.509 certificate that it can present to external entities when establishing cryptographic communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FPT_STM_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to synchronize with an NTP server for reliable time data that is used for establishment of valid cryptographic channels.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FDP_IFC.1</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining an enterprise session controller policy to broker VVoIP endpoint communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FDP_IFF.1</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining the rules enforced by the enterprise session controller policy.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_UAU.2/TC</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring authentication of telecommunications devices that are connected to the TOE before the TSF will interact with them.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_UAU.2/VVoIP</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring authentication of VVoIP endpoints that are connected to the TOE before the TSF will interact with them.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FTP_ITC.1/ESC</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining the trusted channels used for protection of signaling and media data used in VVoIP and SIP trunking communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FPT_TUD_EXT.1/VVoIP (implementation-dependent)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by optionally allowing the TOE to distribute software/firmware updates to connected VVoIP endpoints.</rationale>
			</threat>
			<threat name="T.UNAUTHORIZED_CLIENT" id="t-unauthorized-client"><description>An attacker may attempt to register an unauthorized VVoIP endpoint to the TOE for the purpose of
			impersonating a legitimate end user device in order to gain unauthorized connectivity to other clients
			or active calls.</description>
			<!-- O.SECURE_VVOIP-->
			<addressed-by>FCS_DTLSS_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the use of DTLS to protect transmitted voice/video media if this is the chosen method for securing it.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_DTLSS_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring any implementation of DTLS to use mutual authentication.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_NTP_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to support NTP communications to obtain reliable time data that is used for establishment of valid cryptographic channels.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSC_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSS_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_TLSS_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP and H.323 communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.1/Rev (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring X.509 validation in support of establishing TLS communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring X.509 authentication in support of establishing TLS communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.3 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to be able to request an X.509 certificate that it can present to external entities when establishing cryptographic communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FPT_STM_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to synchronize with an NTP server for reliable time data that is used for establishment of valid cryptographic channels.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FDP_IFC.1</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining an enterprise session controller policy to broker VVoIP endpoint communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FDP_IFF.1</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining the rules enforced by the enterprise session controller policy.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_UAU.2/TC</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring authentication of telecommunications devices that are connected to the TOE before the TSF will interact with them.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FIA_UAU.2/VVoIP</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring authentication of VVoIP endpoints that are connected to the TOE before the TSF will interact with them.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FTP_ITC.1/ESC</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining the trusted channels used for protection of signaling and media data used in VVoIP and SIP trunking communications.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FPT_TUD_EXT.1/VVoIP (implementation-dependent)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by optionally allowing the TOE to distribute software/firmware updates to connected VVoIP endpoints.</rationale>
			<!-- O.SYSTEM_MONITORING-->
			<addressed-by>FAU_GEN.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining additional required auditable events that are specific to ESC functionality that extend the audit generation requirement defined in the Base-PP.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FAU_STG.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring all stored audit data to be protected against unauthorized access.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FCS_NTP_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to support NTP communications to obtain reliable time data that is used for accurate recording of log data.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FPT_STM_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to synchronize with an NTP server for reliable time data that is used for accurate log data.</rationale>
			<comment>this is duplicate from O.System_monitoring and O.SECURE_VVOIP.</comment>
			<addressed-by>FAU_GEN.1/Log</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to generate a real-time system log of its own diagnostic details.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FAU_SAR.1/Log</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining what users are able to review the real-time system log.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FAU_SEL.1 (selection-based)</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by optionally allowing an administrator to suppress the generation of certain audit records.</rationale>
			<addressed-by>FMT_SMF.1/ESC</addressed-by><rationale>This SFR supports the objective by defining the authorized management functions supported by the TOE.</rationale>
			<comment>FMT_SMF.1/ESC mitigates T.UNAUTHORIZED_CLIENT by making it so that VVoIP endpoints can't be registered without authorization</comment>
			</threat>


      </threats>
    </section>  <!-- Threats -->
	
	<!-- Assumptions refer to operational objective objectives regardless of whether -->
	<!-- the document uses standard or direct rationale. -->
	
    <section title="Assumptions" id="sec-assumptions">
	All assumptions for the operational environment of the Base-PP also apply to this PP-Module.
	A.NO_THRU_TRAFFIC_PROTECTION is still operative, but only for the interfaces in the TOE that are
	defined by the Base-PP and not the PP-Module.
      
    </section>   <!-- Assumptions -->
	
	<!-- OSPs refer to Objectives or OE Objectives in standard approach documents. -->
	<!-- In direct rationale PPs, they should refer to OE Objectives -->
    <section title="Organizational Security Policies" id="sec-OSPs">
	The following organizational security policy is applicable to the TOE if the TOE is deployed on an independent, commercially-available operating system:
      <OSPs>
        <OSP name="P.SECURED_PLATFORM">
          <description>Administrators in the organization ensure that general purpose computers use secure operating
		systems and are configured in accordance with applicable security standards.</description>
			<objective-refer ref="OE.SECURED_PLATFORM">
            <rationale>In order to ensure that the ESC is not subject to compromise, it is important for the OS that it is installed on to be secure in terms of closing unnecessary interfaces and providing appropriate security functionality. However,
			it is necessary for this PP-Module to make this
			an organizational policy in the scenario where the TOE uses a commercial third-party OS
			because the ESC vendor is not responsible for
			providing the OS and therefore has no control
			over its inherent functionality or
			administrative configuration.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </OSP>
      </OSPs>
    </section>   <!-- OSPs -->
	
	<!-- If there are no OSPs, then this: -->
<!--	<section title="Organizational Security Policies" id="sec-osp" boilerplate="no">
        <OSPs/>
    </section> 
-->
	
  </section>  <!-- Security Problem Definition -->
  
  
  <!-- This section is mandatory for standard approach documents.   -->
  <!-- It should be included in direct rationale documents if there are OE Objectives. -->
  <section title="Security Objectives" id="sec-objectives">
  

	<!-- This section is included in direct rationale documents if there are OE Objectives -->
    <section title="Security Objectives for the Operational Environment" id="sec-OEObjectives">
	All objectives for the operational environment of the Base-PP also apply to this PP-Module.
	OE.NO_THRU_TRAFFIC_PROTECTION is still operative, but only for the interfaces in the TOE that are
	defined by the Base-PP and not the PP-Module.<h:p>This PP-Module also defines the following additional environmental objective:
	</h:p>
	  <SOEs>
        <SOE name="OE.SECURED_PLATFORM">
          <description>The operating system of the network device does not provide an interface or other capability that can
be used to adversely affect the TOE or its own functionality.</description>
        </SOE>
      </SOEs>
	</section>  <!-- OE Objectives -->

	<!-- This section is automatically generated, but this placeholder is reuired -->
    <section title="Security Objectives Rationale" id="sec-sor"/>
	<h:p>Note that this section only provides mappings for the security objectives defined in this PP-Module.</h:p>

  </section>  <!-- Security_Objectives  -->


  
  <sec:Security_Requirements>
    <base-pp id="ND" version="3.0e" name="Network Device" product="Network Device" short="ND" plural="Network Devices">
      <url>https://www.niap-ccevs.org/protectionprofiles/482</url>
      <cPP/>
      <sec-func-req-dir> <h:p>This section instructs the ST author on what selections must be made to certain SFRs contained in the
NDcPP in order to mitigate the threats defined in this PP-Module or to mitigate a threat from the NDcPP
in a more specific or restrictive manner than what it specifies.</h:p><h:p>
Full assurance activities are not repeated for the requirements in this section; only the additional testing
needed to supplement what has already been captured in the Supporting Documents for the NDcPP is
included.</h:p>

      </sec-func-req-dir>
      <modified-sfrs/>
      <additional-sfrs/>
      <con-toe>
     	When this PP-Module is used to extend the NDcPP, the TOE type for the overall TOE is still a network device. The TOE boundary is simply extended to include ESC functionality that is provided by the network device.
      </con-toe>
      <con-sec-prob>
	 	The threats defined by this PP-Module (see section 3.1) supplement those defined in the NDcPP as follows:
	  </con-sec-prob>
      <con-obj/>
      <con-op-en>The objectives for the TOE’s operational environment are consistent with the NDcPP based on the
following rationale: </con-op-en>
      
      
      <con-mod ref="T.MALICIOUS_TRAFFIC">The Base-PP does not define a threat for malicious traffic because all of its
		security-relevant external interfaces define the network device as the
		endpoint. This PP-Module defines interfaces where the TOE is facilitating a
		connection between two external entities, such that traffic between them will
		flow “through” the TOE as opposed to “to/from the TOE.” This threat is
		consistent with the Base-PP because it is only applied to the interfaces defined
		in this PP-Module where it is relevant; it does not apply to the interfaces
		defined in the Base-PP.
	  </con-mod>
      <con-mod ref="T.NETWORK_DISCLOSURE">
		The Base-PP does not define a threat for access to network resources because
		all of its security-relevant external interfaces define the network device as the
		endpoint. This PP-Module defines interfaces where the TOE is facilitating a
		connection between two external entities, such that traffic between them will
		flow “through” the TOE as opposed to “to/from the TOE.” This threat is
		consistent with the Base-PP because it is only applied to the interfaces defined
		in this PP-Module where it is relevant; it does not apply to the interfaces
		defined in the Base-PP.
	  </con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="T.UNAUTHORIZED_CLIENT">
		This threat is a specific instance of the
		T.WEAK_AUTHENTICATION_ENDPOINTS threat defined in the Base-PP
		because it refers to a scenario where an unauthorized client is able to
		communicate successfully with the TOE because the TSF is incapable of
		authenticating clients to determine which are or are not authorized.
	  </con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="P.SECURED_PLATFORM">
		The Base-PP does not define any policies that expect that environmental
		systems are configured in any specific manner. Therefore, it is expected that requiring environmental systems to be configured in a secure manner will not
		prevent the TSF from being fully implemented.
	  </con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="OE.SECURED_PLATFORM">
		This objective expects the TOE to be configured in such a manner that the
		underlying OS on which the TOE runs cannot be used to alter the behavior of
		the TSF. This is consistent with the OE.NO_GENERAL_PURPOSE objective in
		the Base-PP that expects that general-purpose computing capability will be
		prohibited by the OS. This ensures that OE.SECURED_PLATFORM can be
		satisfied by the operational environment.
	  </con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fau-gen-1-esc">This PP-Module modifies the Base-PP SFR to add specific auditable events that
		relate to ESC functionality.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fau-stg-2-esc">This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this optional SFR because it is
		required to implement functionality required by this PP-Module.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fcs-dtlss-ext-1">This PP-Module refines this selection-based SFR to a more restrictive selection if claimed. The available selection item is one of the items in the original version of the SFR. This PP-Module also specifies an additional trigger for when this SFR must be claimed</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fcs-dtlss-ext-2">This PP-Module conditionally mandates the inclusion of this optional SFR for any situation where DTLS is claimed, which makes this into a selection-based SFR.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fcs-ntp-ext-1">This PP-Module requires NTP v4 to be selected, which is one of two selection
		options defined in the original SFR in the Base-PP. This PP-Module also mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because it is required to
		implement the NTP functionality prompted by the PP-Module’s refinement to
		FPT_STM_EXT.1.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fcs-tlsc-ext-1">This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because it
		is required to implement the trusted communications required by the PPModule.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fcs-tlsc-ext-2">This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this optional SFR because it is
		required to implement the trusted communications required by the PPModule.
		</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fcs-tlss-ext-1">This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because it
		is required to implement the trusted communications required by the PPModule.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fcs-tlss-ext-2">This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this optional SFR because it is
		required to implement the trusted communications required by the PPModule.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fia-x509-ext-1">This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because
		all TOEs that conform to this PP-Module will perform functions that require
		certificate validation.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fia-x509-ext-2">This PP-Module modifies the Base-PP requirement by defining a mandatory
		usage of X.509 certificate authentication and to require the TOE to implement
		at least one trusted protocol that requires certificate validation.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fia-x509-ext-3">This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because
		all TOEs that conform to this PP-Module will perform functions that require
		the TSF to have the ability to issue a certificate request to obtain its own X.509
		certificate.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fpt-stm-ext-1">This PP-Module modifies the Base-PP by requiring one of this SFR’s two
		original selection items to be chosen.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fpt-gen-ext-1-cdr">The PP-Module iterates an SFR defined in the Base-PP to require the TOE to
		generate a type of audit record that is specific to the functions defined in this
		PP-Module.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fpt-gen-ext-1-log">The PP-Module iterates an SFR defined in the Base-PP to require the TOE to
		generate a type of audit record that is specific to the functions defined in this
		PP-Module.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fau-sar-1-log">This PP-Module requires the TOE to implement a mechanism for review of
		system log records that are defined by this PP-Module in FAU_GEN.1/Log and
		does not relate to the audit records required by the Base-PP.
		</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fau-stg-2-cdr">The PP-Module iterates an SFR defined in the Base-PP by protecting audit data
		required by this PP-Module in the same manner that the Base-PP defines for
		its own audit records.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fau-vvr-ext-1">This SFR applies to recording voice and video call data, which is beyond the
		original scope of the Base-PP.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fdp-ifc-1">This SFR applies to the TOE’s implementation of an enterprise session
		controller policy, which applies to the TOE’s through-traffic interfaces and is
		therefore beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fdp-iff-1">This SFR applies to the TOE’s implementation of an enterprise session
		controller policy, which applies to the TOE’s through-traffic interfaces and is
		therefore beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fdp-rip-1">This SFR applies to data wipe operations which is beyond the original scope of
		the Base-PP. The Base-PP defines FCS_CKM.4 for destruction of cryptographic
		data but this PP-Module extends the requirements for data destruction to
		entire disk storage locations.
		</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fia-uau-2-tc">This SFR applies to authentication of external entities on the TOE’s through-traffic interfaces and is therefore beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fia-uau-2-vvoip">This SFR applies to authentication of external entities on the TOE’s through-traffic interfaces and is therefore beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fmt-cfg-ext-1">This SFR requires the TOE to implement a secure default configuration. There
		is no inconsistency here with the Base-PP because the Base-PP’s functionality
		is not dependent on a particular default configuration.
		</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fmt-smf-1-ecs">This SFR requires the TOE to implement management functions that are
specific to ESC functionality. This does not conflict with the Base-PP because
these are all additional functions that go beyond what the Base-PP requires.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fpt-fls-1">This SFR requires the TOE to take some specific action in the event of self-test
failures or other hardware failures. This extends the functionality required by
the Base-PP because the Base-PP defines the self-tests that the TOE must
perform but does not define specific requirements for the TOE’s behavior
when a self-test fails.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="ftp-itc.1-esc">This SFR requires the TOE to implement trusted channels for VVoIP and SIP
trunking communications. This is an iteration of the same Base-PP SFR that
adds new external interfaces beyond the scope of the Base-PP.
</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fpt-tud-ext-1-vvoip">This PP-Module extends the functionality required by the Base-PP by
optionally allowing the TSF to perform software update activities for
connected VVoIP endpoints and not just for the TOE itself.</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fau-sel-1">This PP-Module optionally allows a conformant TOE to claim the ability to
suppress the generation of audit events based on certain factors. This does
not conflict with the Base-PP because if the administrators desires all required
auditable events to be audited, they can choose to disable this function.
</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fau-stg-2-vvr">This PP-Module optionally allows a conformant TOE to claim the ability to
securely store voice/video recordings. This does not conflict with the Base-PP
because the Base-PP already has the ability to define secured storage (e.g.
through FAU_STG.2) so there is no expectation of availability that is being
violated if this is claimed</con-mod>
	  <con-mod ref="fau-vvr-ext-2">This PP-Module optionally allows a conformant TOE to claim the ability to
generate and retain voice/video recordings of calls. This does not conflict with
the Base-PP because the Base-PP already defines an audit mechanism via
FAU_GEN.1 and also does not define any requirements that would prevent
the generation of media recordings such as unobservability of user actions.</con-mod>


	  <modified-sfrs>
	  <audit-table table="mandatory" id="mandatory-audit-events">
	      <h:br/><h:b><ctr ctr-type="Table" pre="Table " id="atref-mandatory">: Audit Log Events</ctr></h:b>
	    </audit-table>
	  <section title="Security Audit (FAU)" id="m-fau">


			<f-component name="Audit Data Generation (Audit Log)" cc-id="fau_gen.1" id="fau-gen-1-esc">FAU_GEN.1.1 is refined to include the following auditable events in addition to what is defined in the
Base-PP.
		<note role="application"><h:i><h:p>The Base-PP version of the SFR requires “all administrative actions” to be audited.
		When the TOE includes this PP-Module, it is expected that this will also include the
		administrative actions that support the PP-Module defined in FMT_SMF.1/ESC.</h:p><h:p>FAU_VVR_EXT.2 is a selection-based requirement. Auditing for this requirement
		must be performed if and only if the TOE claims it</h:p>
		</h:i></note>
		<aactivity>The evaluator shall complete the EA for FAU_GEN.1 as described in the NDcPP SD for the auditable events
defined above in addition to the applicable auditable events that are defined in the NDcPP. The evaluator
shall also ensure that the administrative actions defined for this PP-Module are appropriately audited. </aactivity>

			</f-component>
			<f-component name="Protected Audit Trail Storage" cc-id="fau_stg.2" id="fau-stg-2-esc">This SFR is optional in the NDcPP but is mandated by this PP-Module because the ESC is expected to
	maintain audit data internal to the TOE which must be protected from unauthorized access. 
	<note role="application"><h:i>Both the “audit data” (FAU_GEN.1) and “system log” data (FAU_GEN.1/Log) are
	expected to be protected from unauthorized access. This SFR applies to all data
	related to the behavior of the TOE regardless of how it is categorized or where it
	is stored.</h:i> </note>
	<aactivity>There is no change to the EAs specified for this SFR in the NDcPP SD. The PP-Module modifies this SFR to
make its inclusion mandatory rather than optional, but there is no change to how the SFR is to be
implemented.</aactivity></f-component>
	</section>
	<section title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)" id="m-fcs">
			<f-component name="DTLS Server Support without Mutual Authentication" cc-id="fcs_dtlss_ext.1" id="fcs-dtlss-ext-1">
			<f-element id="fcs-dtlss-ext-1e1">
				<title>
				The TSF shall implement DTLS 1.2 (RFC 6347) supporting the following ciphersuites: <selectables> 	
					<selectable>select supported ciphersuites from List 1<h:b> in the NDcPP</h:b></selectable>
					</selectables>and no other ciphersuites.
				</title>
				<note role="application"><h:i><h:p>This SFR is selection-based in the NDcPP and remains selection-based in this PPModule because DTLS may be used to secure transmitted media. In this case, it
				must be claimed if ‘DTLS’ is selected in FTP_ITC.1.1/ESC in addition to the
				applicable selection triggers in the Base-PP.</h:p>
				<h:p>This SFR is also refined from its definition in the Base-PP by requiring the use of
				DTLS 1.2 if this function is claimed.</h:p><h:p>When CPP_ND_V3.0E is the Base-PP, the element in Section 5.1.2.1 should be used, instead.</h:p>
				</h:i>
				</note>
				<aactivity>There is no change to the EAs specified for this SFR in the NDcPP SD.</aactivity>
				
				</f-element>
			</f-component>
			<f-component name="DTLS Server Support for Mutual Authentication" cc-id="fcs_dtlss_ext.2" id="fcs-dtlss-ext-2">This SFR is optional in the NDcPP but is selection-based in this PP-Module because any ESC use of DTLS
			requires mutually-authenticated DTLS to be implemented. Therefore, this SFR must be claimed if ‘DTLS’ is
			selected in FTP_ITC.1.1/ESC.
			<aactivity>There is no change to the EAs specified for this SFR in the NDcPP SD. The PP-Module modifies this SFR to
			make its inclusion selection-based rather than optional, but there is no change to how the SFR is to be
			implemented.
			</aactivity>
			</f-component>
			<f-component name="NTP Protocol" cc-id="fcs_ntp_ext.1" id="fcs-ntp-ext-1">
			<f-element id="fcs-ntp-ext-1e1">
			<title>The TSF shall use only the following NTP version: NTP v4 (RFC 5905).</title>

			<note role="application"><h:i><h:p>te: This SFR is selection-based in the Base-PP but is mandatory for a TOE that
			conforms to this PP-Module because the refinement to FPT_STM_EXT.1 requires
			this SFR to be claimed in all cases.</h:p><h:p/>This SFR has been refined from the NDcPP to permit the NTP v4 selection only. No
			other parts of the SFR are modified.</h:i></note>
			<aactivity>There is no change to the EAs specified for this SFR in the NDcPP SD. The PP-Module modifies this SFR to
			make its inclusion selection-based rather than optional, but there is no change to how the SFR is to be
			implemented.</aactivity>
			</f-element></f-component>
			<f-component name="TLS Client Protocol without Mutual Authentication" cc-id="fcs_tlsc_ext.1" id="fcs-tlsc-ext-1">
			<f-element id="fcs-tlsc-ext-1e1">
				<title>The TSF shall implement TLS 1.2 (RFC 5246) and reject all other TLS and SSL
				versions. The TLS implementation will support the following ciphersuites:
				<selectables>
					<selectable>select supported ciphersuites from List 1 <h:b>in the NDcPP</h:b></selectable>
				</selectables> and no other ciphersuites.
				<note role="application"><h:i>This SFR is selection-based in the NDcPP but is mandated by this PP-Module
				because Transport Layer Security (TLS) is used to secure SIP and H.323
				communications. Additionally, this PP-Module mandates the use of TLS 1.2. When CPP_ND_V3.0E is the Base-PP, the element in Section 5.1.2.1 should be used, instead.</h:i></note></title>
				<aactivity>There is no change to the EAs specified for this SFR in the NDcPP SD. The PP-Module modifies this SFR to
				make its inclusion mandatory rather than conditional, but there is no change to how the SFR is to be
				implemented.</aactivity>
				</f-element></f-component>
			<f-component name="TLS Client Protocol Mutual Authentication" cc-id="fcs_tlsc_ext.2" id="fcs-tlsc-ext-2">This SFR is optional in the NDcPP but is mandated by this PP-Module because SIP and H.323
			communications require mutually-authenticated TLS.
				<aactivity>There is no change to the EAs specified for this SFR in the NDcPP SD. The PP-Module modifies this SFR to
				make its inclusion mandatory rather than optional, but there is no change to how the SFR is to be
				implemented.</aactivity>
				</f-component>


				<f-component name="TLS Server Protocol without Mutual Authentication" cc-id="fcs_tlss_ext.1" id="fcs-tlss-ext-1">
				<f-element id="fcs-tlss-ext-1e1">
				<title>The TSF shall implement TLS 1.2 (RFC 5246) and reject all other TLS and SSL
				versions. The TLS implementation will support the following ciphersuites: <selectables>
				<selectable>select supported ciphersuites from List 1 <h:b>in the NDcPP</h:b></selectable></selectables> and no other
				ciphersuites.</title>
				<note role="application"><h:i>This SFR is selection-based in the NDcPP but is mandated by this PP-Module
				because TLS is used to secure SIP and H.323 communications. Additionally, this
				PP-Module mandates the use of TLS 1.2. When CPP_ND_V3.0E is the Base-PP, the element in Section 5.1.2.1 should be used, instead.</h:i></note>
				<aactivity>There is no change to the EAs specified for this SFR in the NDcPP SD. The PP-Module modifies this SFR to
				make its inclusion mandatory rather than conditional, but there is no change to how the SFR is to be
				implemented.</aactivity>
				</f-element></f-component>

			<f-component name="TLS Server Protocol  Mutual Authentication" cc-id="fcs_tlss_ext.2" id="fcs-tlss-ext-2">

			This SFR is optional in the NDcPP but is mandated by this PP-Module because SIP and H.323 communications require mutually-authenticated TLS.
			<aactivity>There is no change to the EAs specified for this SFR in the NDcPP SD. The PP-Module modifies this SFR to
make its inclusion mandatory rather than optional, but there is no change to how the SFR is to be
implemented.</aactivity>
			</f-component>
			</section>
			<section title="Identification and Authentication (FIA)" id="m-fia">
			
			<comment>The xml file contains text that has been commented out- in case we need to fall back to the original write up, feel free to comment the section below</comment>
			<!-- The following commented section is used as a placeholder for modification of this requirement-->
			<!-- 
			<base-sfr-spec cc-id="fia_x509_ext.1" title="X.509 Certificate Validation" id="nd-mod-fia-x509-ext-1">
			<consistency-rationale>
						This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because it is a dependency of the TLS requirements that it also mandates.
			</consistency-rationale>
			<description>This SFR is selection-based in the X.509 Functional Package but mandatory in this PP-Module because the TOE’s TLS implementation requires appropriate X.509 functionality. The SFR is unchanged from its original definition.</description><no-change/>
			<set-status status="mandatory"/>
			</base-sfr-spec>
			
			<base-sfr-spec cc-id="fia_x509_ext.2" title="X.509 Certificate Validation" id="nd-mod-fia-x509-ext-2">
			<consistency-rationale>
						This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because it is a dependency of the TLS requirements that it also mandates.
			</consistency-rationale>
			<description>This SFR is selection-based in the X.509 Functional Package but mandatory in this PP-Module because the TOE’s TLS implementation requires appropriate X.509 functionality. The SFR is unchanged from its original definition.</description><no-change/>
			<set-status status="mandatory"/>
			</base-sfr-spec>

			<base-sfr-spec cc-id="fia_x509_ext.3" title="X.509 Certificate Validation" id="nd-mod-fia-x509-ext-3">
			<consistency-rationale>
						This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because it is a dependency of the TLS requirements that it also mandates.
			</consistency-rationale>
			<description>This SFR is selection-based in the X.509 Functional Package but mandatory in this PP-Module because the TOE’s TLS implementation requires appropriate X.509 functionality. The SFR is unchanged from its original definition.</description><no-change/>
			<set-status status="mandatory"/>
			</base-sfr-spec>
			-->
			
			
			<f-component name="X.509 Certificate Validation" cc-id="fia_x509_ext.1" id="fia-x509-ext-1" iteration="Rev">
			This SFR is selection-based in the Base-PP. It is mandatory when the TOE claims conformance to this PPModule because X.509 certificate validation is needed when establishing TLS communications for SIP and H.323. There are no changes to the SFR otherwise.
			<aactivity>No additional EAs are specified for this SFR beyond what is defined in the NDcPP SD.</aactivity>
			</f-component>
			<f-component name="X.509 Certificate Authentication" cc-id="fia_x509_ext.2" id="fia-x509-ext-2">
			<f-element id="fia-x509-ext-2e1">
				<title>The TSF shall use X.509v3 certificates as defined by RFC 5280 to support
authentication for <h:b>TLS,</h:b> <selectables>
			<selectable>DTLS</selectable>
			<selectable>HTTPS</selectable>
			<selectable>IPsec</selectable>
			<selectable>SSH</selectable>
			<selectable>no other protocols</selectable></selectables>, <h:b>VVoIP endpoint registration,</h:b> and  <selectables><selectable>code signing for system software
updates</selectable>
			<selectable><assignable>other uses</assignable></selectable>
			<selectable>no additional</selectable></selectables>
			</title>
			<note role="application">
			<h:i>The NDcPP requires the ST author to select the protocol(s) that certificate
			authentication is used for. This element has been modified from its definition in
			the Base-PP by mandating support for TLS because FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 and
			FCS_TLSS_EXT.2 are mandatory SFRs for a TOE that conforms to this PP-Module.
			Additional protocols may or may not be selected depending on the other
			functionality provided by the TSF</h:i></note>
			</f-element>
			<f-element id="fia-x509-ext-2e2">
			<title>When the TSF cannot establish a connection to determine the validity of a
			certificate, the TSF shall <selectables>
			<selectable>allow the administrator to choose whether to
			accept the certificate in these cases</selectable>
			<selectable>accept the certificate</selectable>
			<selectable>not accept the
			certificate</selectable>
			</selectables>.</title>
			<note role="application"><h:i>This SFR is selection-based in the Base-PP but is made mandatory when this PPModule is claimed because the ESC implements functionality that requires the use of certificate authentication.</h:i></note>
			<aactivity>No additional EAs are specified for this SFR beyond what is defined in the NDcPP SD.</aactivity>
			</f-element>
			
			</f-component>
			<f-component name="X.509 Certificate Requests" cc-id="fia_x509_ext.3" id="fia-x509-ext-3">
			This SFR is selection-based in the NDcPP but is mandated by this PP-Module because an ESC must
			implement security functions that require it to be issued its own X.509 certificate.
			<aactivity>No additional EAs are specified for this SFR beyond what is defined in the NDcPP SD.</aactivity>
			</f-component>
			</section>
		<section title="Protection of the TSF (FPT)" id="m-fpt">
		<f-component name="Reliable Time Stamps" cc-id="fpt_stm_ext.1" id="fpt-stm-ext-1">
		<f-element id="fpt-stm-ext-1e1">
		<title>The TSF shall synchronize time with an NTP server. </title>
		<note role="application"><h:i>This SFR has been refined from the NDcPP to permit the NTP server selection only. No other parts of the SFR are modified.</h:i></note>
		<aactivity>No additional EAs are specified for this SFR beyond what is defined in the NDcPP SD.</aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event/>
		</f-component>
			
			</section>

			<comment>First half of TD0835 has been applied to this document, however the other half of this TD adds a "Further Modified SFRs"- Guidance is needed on how to implement this into the current document </comment>
	  </modified-sfrs>
    </base-pp>
	<man-sfrs>
    <section title="Security Audit (FAU)" id="man-fau">
		<f-component name="Audit Data Generation (Call Detail Record)" cc-id="fau_gen.1" id="fpt-gen-ext-1-cdr" iteration="CDR">
		<f-element id="fau-gen-1e1-cdr">
		<title>The TSF shall be able to generate <h:b>a call detail record (CDR)</h:b> for the following auditable events:
<h:ol type="a">
<h:li><h:s>Start-up and shutdown of the audit functions;</h:s></h:li>
<h:li>All auditable events for the [<h:i>not specified</h:i>]</h:li>
<h:li>[<h:i>communications between VVoIP endpoints that are established by the TOE</h:i></h:li>
</h:ol></title>
		
		</f-element>
		<f-element id="fau-gen-1e2-cdr">
		<title>The TSF shall record within each <h:b>CDR</h:b> at least the following information: 
		<h:ol type="a">
		<h:li><h:s>Date and time of the auditable event, type of event, subject identity (if applicable), and the
outcome (success or failure) of the event;</h:s></h:li>
<h:li>
For each auditable event type, based on the auditable event definitions of the functional
components included in the PP, PP-Module, functional package or ST, [</h:li></h:ol>
		<h:b><h:i><h:lu>
			<h:li>calling party number (i.e. call originator)</h:li>
			<h:li>called party number (i.e. call receiver or terminating number)</h:li>
			<h:li>unique transaction sequence number</h:li>
			<h:li>call disposition (e.g. call connected, call terminated, call transferred)</h:li>
			<h:li>call type (e.g. voice only, voice and video, text)</h:li>
			<h:li>call start time</h:li>
			<h:li>call end time</h:li>
			<h:li>call duration</h:li>
			<h:li>unique identifier of the TOE</h:li>
			<h:li>call routing into TOE</h:li>
			<h:li>call routing out of TOE</h:li>
			<h:li>time zone</h:li>
			<h:li>call release cause, if applicable (i.e. reason for termination of call)</h:li>
			<h:li>fault condition(s), if applicable</h:li>
		</h:lu></h:i></h:b>].

		
		</title>
		<note role="application"><h:i>The TOE should be uniquely identified as part of the CDR so that there is
		attribution of individual CDRs in environments where multiple ESCs are feeding
		CDRs to a centralized server.</h:i></note>
		<aactivity>
			<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes the format of the Call Detail Records (CDRs) generated by the TOE in sufficient detail to demonstrate that the requirement is satisfied.</TSS>
			<Guidance>The evaluator shall examine the guidance documentation to determine that it describes the format of
			CDRs in sufficient detail for the reader to understand their contents and any configuration actions that
			are required in order for the CDRs to include the data that is mandated by this PP-Module.</Guidance>
			<Tests><h:p>Note that these test activities may be performed in conjunction with other tests. 
			</h:p><h:p>The evaluator shall deploy the TOE in an environment where it can be used to establish calls for a
			supported signaling protocol (i.e. Session Initiation Protocol (SIP), H.323). The evaluator shall place a call
			between two VVoIP endpoints, allow it to remain connected for three minutes, and then hang up. The
			evaluator shall then verify that the TOE generated CDRs for this call that contain all necessary information
			in the format specified by the operational guidance and that this information is accurate. The evaluator
			shall then place a second call where the call is transferred to a third VVoIP endpoint prior to termination.</h:p><h:p>The evaluator shall repeat this testing for each type of signaling protocol supported by the TOE.</h:p></Tests>
		</aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event/>
		</f-component>
		<f-component name="Audit Data Generation (System Log)" cc-id="fau_gen.1" id="fpt-gen-ext-1-log" iteration="Log">
		<f-element id="fau-gen-1e1-log">
		<title>
		The TSF shall be able to generate <h:b>system log</h:b> of the following auditable events:
			<h:ol type="a">
			<h:li><h:s>Start-up and shutdown of the audit functions;</h:s></h:li>
			<h:li>All auditable events for the [<h:i>not specified</h:i>]</h:li>
			<h:li>[<h:b>current IP connections, NTP status, CPU usage, memory usage, disk and file storage capacity, audit storage capacity, <selectables><selectable>power Status</selectable><selectable>fan status</selectable><selectable>no other activities</selectable></selectables></h:b></h:li>
			</h:ol>
		
		</title>
		
		</f-element>
		<f-element id="fau-gen-1e2-log">
		<title>
		The TSF shall record within <h:b>each system log</h:b> data at least the following information:
		<h:ol>
		<h:li>Date and time of the auditable event, type of event, subject identity (if applicable), and the outcome (success or failure) of the event;</h:li>
		<h:li>For each auditable event type, based on the auditable event definitions of the functional
components included in the PP, PP-Module, functional package or ST, [<h:i>event details described in System Log Events table</h:i>].</h:li>
		</h:ol>
		
    <h:head><title><h:b><ctr ctr-type="Table" pre="Table " id="atref-mandatory">: System Log Events</ctr></h:b></title></h:head>
<h:table border="1">
		<h:tr>
			<h:th>Event</h:th>
			<h:th>Additional System Log Record Contents</h:th>
			
		</h:tr>
		<h:tr>
			<h:th>Current IP connections</h:th>
			<h:th>Network interface card (NIC); Status (up or down).</h:th>
		</h:tr>
				<h:tr>
			<h:th>CPU usage </h:th>
			<h:th>Utilization percentage of TOE CPU(s).</h:th>
		</h:tr>
				<h:tr>
			<h:th>Memory usage</h:th>
			<h:th>Percentage and/or amount of free memory available for use.</h:th>
		</h:tr>
				<h:tr>
			<h:th>Disk and file storage capacity</h:th>
			<h:th>Percentage and/or amount of available space remaining for each disk or disk partition on the TOE.</h:th>
		</h:tr>
				<h:tr>
			<h:th>Fan status (conditional)</h:th>
			<h:th>Fan identification; Status (on or off).</h:th>
		</h:tr>
				<h:tr>
			<h:th>Power status (conditional) </h:th>
			<h:th>Status (on or off).</h:th>
		</h:tr>

		</h:table>

</title>
<note role="application"><h:i><h:p>Unlike audit data (see FAU_GEN.1), system log data is used primarily for real-time
analysis of system behavior. This data is expected to be treated as non-persistent
data by the TOE.</h:p>
<h:p>The ST author is expected to identify the sampling interval for the information
presented in the system log so that it is clear to the evaluator how often updates
to that information will be presented to an administrator</h:p><h:p>Logging of power status is optional and is only intended for TOEs that have
multiple redundant power supplies. Logging of fan status is also optional.</h:p></h:i></note>
<aactivity>
<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that and ensure that it mentions the system log and
describes how the log is presented. Each type of entry in the system log shall be listed along with a brief
description of each content field and what the sampling interval for the data is. The evaluator shall also
check to make sure that every log type mandated by the PP-Module is described and that the description
of the content fields contains the information required in FAU_GEN.1.2/Log.</TSS>
<Guidance>The evaluator shall check the guidance documentation and ensure any configuration necessary to ensure
the TOE generates the required system log is included. The evaluator shall also check that each required
system log item is described in the guidance documentation along with each required content field.</Guidance>
<Tests>The evaluator shall perform the following tests: 
	<testlist>
		<test id="fau-log-current-ip-connection">(current IP connections): First, confirm TOE is connected via IP by pinging it from a remote device.
		Once IP is confirmed connected, take down IP connection either by physically disconnecting network cable
		from the TOE’s NIC; or as TOE Administrator, issue command to logically take down IP connection. Peruse
		system logs to confirm IP connection is down. After confirming IP connection as down, reconnect IP or
		logically bring up IP connection and confirm IP status as up. Repeat for each physical network interface of
		the TOE.</test>
		<test id="fau-log-cpu-usage">(CPU usage): The evaluator shall use the TOE and monitor the CPU usage status over a period of 10
		minutes and observe that fluctuations in CPU usage are reported. It is not necessary to verify that this
		information is accurate at a low level but the evaluator is expected to justify at a high level why these
		fluctuations are occurring (e.g. CPU usage spikes while the TOE is establishing a call).
		</test>
		<test id="fau-log-memory-usage">(memory usage): The evaluator shall use the TOE and monitor the memory usage status over a
		period of 10 minutes and observe that fluctuations in memory usage are reported. It is not necessary to
		verify that this information is accurate at a low level but the evaluator is expected to justify at a high level
		why these fluctuations are occurring (e.g. memory usage spikes while the TOE is establishing a call or
		downloading an update).</test>
		<test id="fau-log-disk-and-file-storage-capacity">(disk and file storage capacity): The evaluator shall use the TOE and monitor the disk capacity status
		over a period of 10 minutes and observe that fluctuations in storage capacity are reported. It is not
		necessary to verify that this information is accurate at a low level but the evaluator is expected to justify
		at a high level why these changes are occurring (e.g. the evaluator transfers a file with a known file size to
		a disk partition and observes that the available space decreased by a corresponding amount).</test>
		<test id="fau-log-fan-status">(fan status) (conditional): First, confirm fan is working as designed. Once fan is confirmed
		functioning properly, disconnect fan to shut it down. Peruse system logs to confirm fan has been reported
		as down. After confirming fan as down, reconnect fan and confirm fan as up. Repeat this process for each
		fan that is monitored by the TSF.</test>
		<test id="fau-log-power-status">(power status): <testlist>
			<test id="fau-log-power-status-redundant"> (conditional): If TOE employs redundant power supplies (PS), then test may be a simple matter of
			cycling one PS while leaving other power units untouched. Reset one PS while allowing the other(s) to
			remain up. Peruse system log and verify message indicating PS cycled (went down &amp; up).</test>
			<test id="fau-log-power-status-single">(conditional): If TOE is supported by a single PS, than test has to be verified by waiting for system
			log to provide power status on periodic intervals. If system log does not report power status, then PS test
			failed.</test>
		</testlist></test>
		</testlist></Tests>
</aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event/>
		</f-component>

		<f-component name="Audit Review (System Log)" cc-id="fau_sar.1" id="fau-sar-1-log" iteration="Log">
		<f-element id="fau-sar-1e1">
		<title>The TSF shall provide <assignable>authorized users</assignable> with the capability to read <assignable>list of audit information</assignable> from the <h:b>system log</h:b> records.
		</title>
		</f-element>
		<f-element id="fau-sar-1e2">
		<title>The TSF shall provide the <h:b>system log</h:b> records in a <h:b>real-time first-in first-out scrolling method</h:b>.</title>
		<aactivity>
			<TSS>There are no TSS EAs for this SFR.</TSS>
			<Guidance>There are no guidance EAs for this SFR.</Guidance>
			<Tests>For each system log event described in FAU_GEN.1.1/Log, the evaluator shall review the system log to
			observe that they are displayed in real time. For those system log events that are periodic or persistent
			status messages, the evaluator shall observe that they are shown in the system log at the proper time.
			For those events that are triggered by a certain event, the evaluator shall cause that event to occur and
			ensure that it is logged. For example, the evaluator shall verify that the TOE logs data link connection
			status by unplugging and reconnecting the TOE’s Ethernet connection and verifying that an appropriate
			log was generated for both. In all cases, the evaluator shall verify that the contents and formatting of the
			log data are consistent with what is defined in FAU_GEN.1.2/Log.
			</Tests>
		</aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event/>
		</f-component>

		<f-component name="Protected Audit Trail Storage (Call Detail Record)" cc-id="fau_stg.2" id="fau-stg-2-cdr" iteration="CDR">
		<f-element id="fau-stg-2e1-cdr">
		<title>The TSF shall protect the stored <h:b>call detail records</h:b> from unauthorized <h:b>disclosure and</h:b> deletion.</title>
		</f-element>
		<f-element id="fau-stg-2e2-cdr">
		<title>The TSF shall be able to [<h:i>prevent</h:i>] unauthorized modifications to the stored <h:b>call
detail records</h:b>.</title>
		<aactivity>
		<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes how CDRs are protected against unauthorized
		modification or deletion. The evaluator shall also examine the TSS to ensure it describes any
		administrative access controls placed on CDR modification (e.g., Administrator Type 1 can modify/delete
		CDRs while Administrator Type 2 cannot modify/delete CDRs).</TSS>
		<Guidance>The evaluator shall examine the guidance documentation to determine that it describes any configuration
		required for protection of the locally stored CDRs against unauthorized modification. The evaluator shall
		also examine the documentation to ensure that any administrative access controls and configuration of
		the access controls on CDR access are described.</Guidance>
		<Tests><h:p>The evaluator shall log in to the TOE as a Security Administrator and verify that authorized administrators
		are able to view stored CDRs but have no ability to modify them.</h:p><h:p>If an administrator access control restricts a user associated with the Security Administrator role from accessing CDR data, the evaluator shall then log in to the TOE as the user that lacks privilege to interact
		with CDRs and observe that there is no way for that user to access the CDR data.</h:p></Tests>
		</aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event/>
		</f-component>

		<ext-comp-def title="Voice and Video Recording" fam-id="FAU_VVR_EXT">
<fam-behavior>This family defines requirements for recording of voice and video data.</fam-behavior>
</ext-comp-def>

		<f-component name="Recording Voice and Video Call Data" cc-id="fau_vvr_ext.1" id="fau-vvr-ext-1">
			<comp-lev> requires the TSF to specify whether or not it records voice and video call data.</comp-lev>
			<management>The following actions could be considered for the management functions in FMT: <h:ul><h:li>Ability to enable/disable voice and video recordings</h:li></h:ul></management>
			<audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
			<dependencies>No dependencies.</dependencies>
			<comment>Audit and dependencies- aren't being generated for the extended component list(Appendix C). Also the selection base box is not being successfully generated. I think this has to do with the fact that the f-element is not established.</comment>
		<title>The TSF shall <selectables>
		<selectable id="fau-vvr-ext-1-1-have">have</selectable>
		<selectable>not have</selectable>
		</selectables> the capability to record voice and video
call data.</title>
		<note role="application"><h:i>If "have" is selected, both FAU_STG.2/VVR and FAU_VVR_EXT.2 must be claimed
		and “Ability to enable/disable voice and video recordings for any registered VVoIP
		endpoint” must be selected in FMT_SMF.1.1/ESC.
		</h:i></note>
		<aactivity>
		<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it describes if the TSF has or does not have the capability to record voice and video call data.</TSS>
		<Guidance>There are no guidance EAs for this SFR.</Guidance>
		<Tests>The test for this SFR is performed as part of FMT_SMF.1/ESC’s EAs.</Tests>
		</aactivity>
		<audit-event/>
		</f-component>
	</section>


	<section title="User Data Protection (FDP)" id="man-fdp">
		<f-component name="Subset Information Flow Control" cc-id="fdp_ifc.1" id="fdp-ifc-1">
		<f-element id="fdp-ifc-1e1">
		<title>
			The TSF shall enforce the [<h:b><h:i>enterprise session controller SFP</h:i></h:b>] on [<h:b><h:i>caller-callee pairs attempting to communicate through the TOE</h:i></h:b>].
			</title>
		<aactivity>This SFR is tested in conjunction with FDP_IFF.1.</aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event/>
		</f-component>

		<f-component name="Simple Security Attributes" cc-id="fdp_iff.1" id="fdp-iff-1">
		<f-element id="fdp-iff-1e1">
		<title>The TSF shall enforce the [<h:b><h:i>enterprise session controller SFP</h:i></h:b>] based on the following types of subject and information security attributes: <h:b><assignable>method by which the TSF identifies each endpoint for a call</assignable> using the following call control protocols: <selectables><selectable>SIP</selectable><selectable>H.323</selectable></selectables> and <selectables><selectable>SS7</selectable><selectable>MGCP</selectable><selectable>no other call control protocols</selectable></selectables></h:b>.
		</title>
		</f-element>
		<f-element id="fdp-iff-1e2">
		<title>The TSF shall permit an information flow between a controlled subject and controlled information via a controlled operation if the following rules hold: [<h:i>when valid communication through the TOE is attempted, the TSF will establish
		a connection between itself and the caller; the TSF will establish a second
		connection between itself and the callee; and the TSF will redirect all
		communications that it receives between the two endpoints out through the
		proper connection</h:i>].</title>
		</f-element>
		<f-element id="fdp-iff-1e3">
		<title>The TSF shall enforce the [<h:i>additional information flow control SFP rules: no additional rules</h:i>].</title>
		</f-element>
		<f-element id="fdp-iff-1e4">
		<title>The TSF shall explicitly authorize an information flow based on the following rules: <assignable>rules, based on security attributes, that explicitly authorize information flows</assignable>.</title>
		<note role="application"><h:i>The expectation of this element is that the ST author define any explicit allowlist
		behavior that overrides the normal information flow handling to automatically
		open a communications channel through the TOE. It is acceptable to complete the
		assignment with “no additional rules” if there are no exceptions to the behavior
		defined in FDP_IFF.1.2 and 1.3.</h:i></note>
		</f-element>
		<f-element id="fdp-iff-1e5">
		<title>The TSF shall explicitly deny an information flow based on the following rules: <assignable>rules, based on security attributes, that explicitly deny information flows</assignable></title>
		<note role="application"><h:i>The expectation of this element is that the ST author define any explicit denylist
		behavior that overrides the normal information flow handling to automatically
		block a communications channel through the TOE. It is acceptable to complete the
		assignment with “no additional rules” if there are no exceptions to the behavior
		defined in FDP_IFF.1.2 and 1.3.</h:i></note>
		<aactivity>
		<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it describes the call control protocol(s) used by the TOE
		and the circumstances under which the TSF will transmit streaming media data. The evaluator shall verify
		that the TSF does not transmit any streaming media in circumstances where a VVoIP endpoint operator
		would not reasonably expect it to do so and whether there are any explicit overrides to the policy.</TSS>
		<Guidance>If any aspects of the TOE’s call control functionality are configurable (such as the specific call control
		protocol used or the circumstances in which the TSF will or will not transmit streaming media data), the
		evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to verify that instructions for configuring this behavior
		are provided.</Guidance>
		<Tests>
		<h:p>The evaluator shall perform one or more of the following tests depending on the protocols that the TOE
		claims to support. For each test performed, the evaluator shall conduct the test for each supported
		environment (IPv4 and/or IPv6).</h:p>
		<h:p><h:b>If the TSF supports SIP:</h:b></h:p>
		<h:p>The evaluator shall set up a test environment where two SIP clients are registered to the TOE and the TSF
		is configured to allow call signals to capture through it. The evaluator shall use a packet sniffer to capture
		call-signaling packets traversing the TOE. The evaluator shall place a call from one SIP client to the other
		and observe via packet capture that two separate SIP connections are established: one from the caller to
		the TOE and the other from the TOE to the callee.</h:p>
		<h:p><h:b>If the TSF supports H.323:</h:b></h:p>
		<h:p>The evaluator shall set up a test environment where two H.323 clients are registered to the TOE and the
		TSF is configured to allow call signals to capture through it. The evaluator shall use a packet sniffer to
		capture call-signaling packets traversing the TOE. The evaluator shall place a call from one H.323 client to
		the other and observe via packet capture that two separate H.323 connections are established: one from
		the caller to the TOE and the other from the TOE to the callee.</h:p>
		<h:p><h:b>If the TSF supports SS7:</h:b></h:p>
		<h:p>Unlike H.323 &amp; SIP which are call-setup and teardown protocols primarily used to process calls between
		local VVoIP endpoints that are registered to the ESC, the SS7 protocol focuses on setup and teardown of
		calls over the legacy Public Switch Telephone Network (PSTN). Therefore, when assessing the SS7 protocol, the evaluator will need to configure the TOE to make a call from a local VVoIP endpoint through
		its SS7 interface to a remote endpoint.</h:p><h:p>The evaluator shall set up a test environment where a single VVoIP endpoint is registered to the TOE
		(through H.323 or SIP) and the TSF is configured to allow call signals through it. The evaluator shall use a
		packet sniffer to capture call-signaling packets traversing the TOE. The evaluator shall place a call from
		the locally registered VVoIP endpoint to a remote endpoint that requires the use of the TOE’s SS7
		extension. The evaluator shall observe and capture SS7 signaling messages transiting through the TOE to
		both the local client and remote SS7-based endpoint. The evaluator shall verify that the TOE successfully
		sets up, processes, and tears down call between local VVoIP endpoint and external telephony device
		requiring SS7 signaling for connectivity. The evaluator shall also verify that the TOE transmits and receives
		the SS7 signaling messages IAM, ACM, and ANM to set up a call and RLC to tear down a call. The evaluator
		shall verify that SS7 call processing is employed by verifying that a two-way conversation can occur over
		the connected call.</h:p><h:p>If the TSF supports both H.323 and SIP, the evaluator shall repeat this test for the VVoIP endpoint
		registration method not chosen during the first iteration of the test</h:p>
		<h:p><h:b>If the TSF supports MGCP:</h:b></h:p><h:p>Unlike H.323 &amp; SIP which are call-setup and teardown protocols primarily used to process calls between
		local VVoIP-clients that are registered to the ESC, the MGCP protocol focuses on the control of Media
		Gateways (MG) which set up voice calls between VVoIP networks and the PSTN. The TSF employs MGCP
		to control MGs that provision VVoIP calls for external connection to the PSTN and from the PSTN to the
		local VVoIP network. Therefore, when assessing the SS7 protocol, the evaluator will need to configure the
		TOE to make a call from a local VVoIP-client through its MGCP interface (i.e. MGC/Call Agent) to a remote
		endpoint.</h:p><h:p>The evaluator shall set up a test environment where a single VVoIP endpoint is registered to the TOE
		(through H.323 or SIP) and the TSF is configured to allow call signals through it. The evaluator shall use a
		packet sniffer to capture call-signaling packets traversing the TOE. The evaluator shall place a call from
		the locally registered VVoIP endpoint to a remote endpoint that requires the use of the TOE’s MGCP
		extension for PSTN connection. The evaluator shall observe and capture MGCP signaling messages
		transiting the TOE to/from the local VVoIP endpoint and out to remote MGCP/PSTN endpoint. The
		evaluator shall verify that the TOE successfully sets up, processes, and tears down the call between the
		local VVoIP endpoint and external telephony device requiring MGC/PSTN signaling for connectivity. The
		evaluator shall also verify that the TOE transmits and receives the MGCP signaling messages NTFY, CRCX,
		and MDCX to set up a call and DLCX to tear down a call. The evaluator shall verify that MGCP call processing
		is employed by verifying that a two-way conversation can occur over the connected call.</h:p><h:p>If the TSF supports both H.323 and SIP, the evaluator shall repeat this test for the VVoIP endpoint
		registration method not chosen during the first iteration of the test.
		</h:p>
		</Tests>
		</aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event/>
		</f-component>


	<f-component name="Subset Residual Information Protection" cc-id="fdp_rip.1" id="fdp-rip-1">
		<f-element id="fdp-rip-1e1">
		<title>The TSF shall ensure that any previous information content of a resource is made
	unavailable upon the <selectables><selectable>allocation of the resource to</selectable><selectable>deallocation of the
	resource from</selectable></selectables> the following objects: <assignable>disk storage location(s) erased
	by the TSF during factory reset or other wipe operation</assignable>.</title>
	<note role="application"><h:i>The TOE is expected to follow guidelines for [NIST SP 800-88], ‘Disk Storage
	Sanitization’ as the method for ensuring that residual information is cleared from
	both volatile and nonvolatile memory. This involves overwriting the entire disk or
	disk partition with zeroes, followed by all ones, followed by all zeroes. Since it is
	not feasible to pause the wipe operation while in progress it is sufficient for the evaluator to observe during testing that the final result is all zeroes; however, the
	vendor-provided evidence is expected to provide a justification that [NIST SP 800-
	88] guidelines are being followed.</h:i></note>
	<aactivity>
	<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes the data objects overwritten as part of the
	sanitation operation. This should include both the TSF data that is overwritten as well as the characteristics of the physical drive that is erased (e.g. an entire drive, one or more logical partitions of a
	drive). The evaluator shall also examine the TSS to ensure that the sanitation process is described. In
	particular, the TSS must describe how the sanitation process follow the NIST 800-88 guidelines for "Disk
	Storage Sanitation."</TSS>
	<Guidance>The evaluator shall examine the guidance documentation to ensure it describes the data objects
	overwritten as part of the sanitation operation. The evaluation shall also ensure that the guidance
	documentation describes the administrative procedures necessary to trigger the sanitation operation. The
	evaluation shall also ensure that the TOE indication that the sanitization operation has completed is
	described, if applicable. </Guidance>
	<Tests>
	<h:p>The following test may require the evaluator to have access to developer tools.</h:p><h:p>The evaluator shall identify the storage locations (e.g. drives, disk partitions) that are erased when the
	TOE performs a wipe operation. The evaluator shall then populate each of these locations with large
	amounts of ‘junk’ data so that a known amount of their storage is used. The evaluator shall use the TOE
	to verify that the current storage levels are consistent with the amount of data that was introduced to
	each location.</h:p><h:p>The evaluator shall then initiate a wipe command and observe that each location that is subject to erasure
	is 100% free. The evaluator shall use forensic tools to examine each location that is subject to erasure and
	verify that the data has been overwritten by all zeroes.</h:p></Tests></aactivity>
	</f-element>
	<audit-event/>
	</f-component>
	</section>


	<section title="Identification and Authentication (FIA)" id="man-fia">
	<f-component name="User Authentication before Any Action (Telecommunications Devices)" cc-id="fia_uau.2" id="fia-uau-2-tc" iteration="TC">
	<f-element id="fia-uau-2e1-tc">
	<title>The TSF shall require each <h:b>telecommunications device</h:b> to be successfully
	authenticated before allowing any other TSF-mediated actions on behalf of that
	<h:b>device</h:b>.</title>
	<aactivity>
	<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS and ensure that the telecommunications device authentication
	procedures are described including a description of how the TOE prevents TSF-mediated actions by
	unauthenticated devices.</TSS>
	<Guidance>The evaluator shall examine the guidance documentation and ensure that any actions required to enable
	authentication of telecommunications devices is described.</Guidance>
	<Tests>
	<h:p>The following testing shall be repeated for each supported environment (IPv4 and/or IPv6):</h:p>
	<h:p>The evaluator shall deploy the TOE in an environment with another ESC and configure both ESCs to
	support an encrypted trunk to one another, where the trunk is encrypted using a security protocol
	selected in FTP_ITC.1 from the Base-PP. The evaluator shall also deploy a packet sniffer on the encrypted
	trunk channel. The evaluator shall perform the following tests:</h:p>
	<testlist>
		<test>The evaluator shall configure the TOE to accept encrypted trunk communications from the remote
		ESC using authentication credentials and IP address. The evaluator shall then use the remote ESC to
		connect to the TOE and verify that the encrypted trunk is successfully established. The evaluator shall use
		packet captures to verify that encrypted traffic is transmitted between the TOE and the remote ESC.</test>
		<test>The evaluator shall repeat test 1 but enter invalid credentials when attempting to authenticate.
		The evaluator shall observe that the encrypted trunk is not successfully established due to invalid
		credentials.</test>
		<test>The evaluator shall repeat test 1 but configure the TOE to accept encrypted trunk communications
		from a different IP address than what is assigned to the remote ESC. The evaluator shall then attempt to
		connect to the TOE using the remote ESC with valid credentials and observe that the encrypted trunk is
		not successfully established due to invalid IP address.</test>
</testlist></Tests></aactivity>
	</f-element>
	<audit-event>
	<audit-event-descr>Successful or failed authentication
of trunk connected network
component</audit-event-descr>
<audit-event-info>ID of Administrator that attempts to connect trunk to
external device (if available);</audit-event-info>
<audit-event-info>IP address of device where trunk request was
initiated (if available);</audit-event-info>
<audit-event-info>IP address of external device where trunk is to be
connected (if available).</audit-event-info>
	</audit-event>
	</f-component>

	<f-component name="User Authentication before Any Action (VVoIP Endpoints)" cc-id="fia_uau.2" id="fia-uau-2-vvoip" iteration="VVoIP">
	<f-element id="fia-uau.2e1-vvoip">
	<title>The TSF shall require each <h:b>VVoIP endpoint</h:b> to be successfully authenticated before allowing any other TSF-mediated actions on behalf of that <h:b>endpoint</h:b>.</title>
	<note role="application"><h:i> This includes both the establishment of voice/video calls and the TOE-initiated application of an update to the VVoIP endpoint software/firmware.</h:i></note>
	<aactivity>
		<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS and ensure that the VVoIP endpoint authentication procedures are
		described including a description of how the TOE prevents TSF-mediated actions by unauthenticated
		devices. In addition to establishment of voice/video calls, this includes TOE-initiated application of an
		update to the VVoIP endpoint software/firmware.</TSS>
		<Guidance>The evaluator shall examine the guidance documentation and ensure that any actions required to
		authenticate VVoIP endpoints are described.</Guidance>
		<Tests><h:p>The following testing shall be repeated for each supported environment (IPv4 and/or IPv6):</h:p><h:p>The evaluator shall ensure that the TSF is configured to support encrypted SIP and/or H.323 client
		connections and that any VVoIP endpoint devices used for this testing can use the protocol that the TSF
		is configured to support.</h:p><h:p>The evaluator shall perform the following tests:</h:p><testlist>
		<test>The evaluator shall attempt to place a call with a VVoIP endpoint device without registering to the
		TOE. The attempt should fail. The evaluator shall also attempt to download an update from the TOE and
		observe failure.</test>
		<test>[Conditional on TOE requiring certificate authentication to establish the connection used for
		registration]: The evaluator shall load an invalid certificate onto a VVoIP endpoint device and initiate the
		registration process. The registration process should fail due to an invalid certificate.</test>
		<test>The evaluator shall connect to the TOE and initiate the registration process. When prompted for
		credentials, the evaluator shall supply invalid credentials and observe that the registration process fails
		for that reason.</test>
		<test>The evaluator shall connect to the TOE and initiate the registration process. When prompted for
		credentials, the evaluator shall supply valid credentials and observe that the registration process succeeds
		and that the registered device can be used to place calls.</test>
		</testlist></Tests></aactivity>
	</f-element>
	

	<audit-event>
	<audit-event-descr>Authentication of external VVoIP
	endpoint/device</audit-event-descr>
	<audit-event-info>ID of Administrator that attempts to connect trunk to
external device (if available);</audit-event-info>
<audit-event-info>IP address of device where trunk request was
initiated (if available);</audit-event-info>
<audit-event-info>IP address of external device where trunk is to be
connected (if available).</audit-event-info>
	<audit-event-info>FIA_UAU.2/VVoIP. Authentication of external VVoIP
	endpoints must occur before registration. In short,
	no successful registration of VVoIP endpoint can
	happen until after the successful authentication of
	the VVoIP endpoint.</audit-event-info>
	</audit-event>
	<audit-event>
	<audit-event-descr>Successful or failed registration of
	VVoIP endpoint/device
	</audit-event-descr>
	<audit-event-info>ID of Administrator that attempt to register VVoIP
	endpoint to TOE (if available);</audit-event-info>
	<audit-event-info>IP address of device where registration attempt was
	initiated (if available);
	</audit-event-info>
	<audit-event-info>IP address of VVoIP endpoint that attempt to register
	to ESC (if available).</audit-event-info>
	</audit-event>
	</f-component>
	</section>

	<section title="Security Management (FMT)" id="man-fmt">

	<ext-comp-def title="Secure by Default Configuration" fam-id="FMT_CFG_EXT">
<fam-behavior>This family defines requirements for protecting the TSF and its data from unauthorized access.</fam-behavior>
</ext-comp-def>
	<f-component name="Secure by Default Configuration" cc-id="fmt_cfg_ext.1" id="fmt-cfg-ext-1">
	<comp-lev>requires credentials to be administratively-defined
before allowing any other TSF-mediated security functionality and to enforce a deny-by-default
posture on the TOE.</comp-lev>
<management>No specific management functions are identified.</management>
<audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
<dependencies><h:p>FIA_UAU.1 Timing of Authentication</h:p><h:p>FMT_MTD.1 Management of TSF Data</h:p><h:p>FMT_SMR.1 Security Roles
</h:p></dependencies>
		<f-element id="fmt-cfg-ext-1e1">
		<title>The TSF shall provide only enough functionality to set new Security
		Administrator credentials when configured with default credentials or no
		credentials</title>	
		</f-element>
		<f-element id="fmt-sfg-ext-1e2">
		<title>The TSF shall be configured by default with permissions which protect it and its data from unauthorized access.</title>
		<aactivity>
		<TSS>The evaluator shall check the TSS and ensure that it identifies if the TOE is delivered with default or no
		Security Administrative credentials. The evaluator shall also check the TSS and ensure that the
		functionality available when the TOE is configured with default credentials or no credentials is identified.
		The evaluator shall examine the identified functionality and ensure that only enough functionality to set
		new Security Administrator credentials is available when the TOE is configured with default credentials or
		no credentials.</TSS>
		<Guidance>The evaluator shall check the guidance documentation and ensure that the administrative functionality
		that is available when the TOE is configured with default credentials or no credentials is identified. The
		evaluator shall examine the guidance documentation and ensure the instructions for establishing new
		Security Administrative credentials is described.
		</Guidance>
		<Tests><h:p>Note that this test may only be deployed the first time the TOE is run or immediately following a factory
		reset.</h:p><h:p>The evaluator shall perform the initial setup steps for the TOE as specified in the administrative guidance.
		The evaluator shall verify that if a default administrative account is used to log in to the TOE for the first
		time, the login event is immediately followed by a prompt to change the password for the default account.
		If no default account is used, the evaluator shall verify that they are prompted to define an initial
		administrator account and that no further security-relevant actions can be performed until the evaluator
		has authenticated to the TOE using that account.</h:p></Tests></aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event table=""/>
	</f-component>
	<f-component name="Specification of Management Functions (ESC)" cc-id="fmt_smf.1" id="fmt-smf-1-ecs" iteration="ESC">
	<f-element id="fmt-smf-1-1-esc">
	<title>The TSF shall be capable of performing the following management functions: [<h:ul>
		<h:li><h:i>Ability to display the real-time connection status of all VVoIP endpoints (hardware and software) and telecommunications devices;</h:i></h:li>
		<h:li><h:i>Ability to clear all TSF data stored on disk;</h:i></h:li>
		<h:li><selectables linebreak="yes">
		<selectable>Ability to configure the password policy;</selectable>
		<selectable id="fmt-smf-1-1-esc-select2">Ability to specify the set of audited events;</selectable>
		<selectable>Ability to configure the behavior of the TOE in response to a self-test failure;</selectable>
		<selectable>Ability to enable/disable voice and video recordings for any registered VVoIP endpoint;</selectable>
		<selectable>Ability to specify criteria for retention of voice and video recordings;</selectable>
		<selectable>No other capabilities</selectable>
		</selectables>].</h:li>
		</h:ul></title>
		<note role="application"><h:i><h:p>This SFR defines additional management functions for the TOE beyond what is
		defined in the Base-PP as FMT_SMF.1. The TOE may have all management
		functionality implemented in the same logical interface; it is not necessary for “network device management” and “enterprise session controller management”
		to be implemented in separate interfaces. </h:p><h:p>The TOE developer is encouraged, but not required, to provide a more
		sophisticated password strength policy than what is prescribed by
		FIA_PMG_EXT.1 as defined in the NDcPP. This may include the ability for an
		administrator to configure the metrics used to define an acceptable password. At
		minimum, the minimum password length must be configurable. If "have” is
		selected in FAU_VVR_EXT.1.1, then "Ability to enable/disable voice and video
		recordings for any registered VVoIP endpoint" must be selected.
		</h:p><h:p>The selection “Ability to configure NTP” must be included in the ST if the TOE uses
		NTP for timestamp configuration. If selected, FCS_NTP_EXT.1 from the NDcPP
		must be claimed as well.</h:p><h:p>If “Ability to specify the set of audited events” is selected, FAU_SEL.1 must be
		claimed.
		</h:p></h:i></note>
		<aactivity>
		<TSS>For each management function specified in FMT_SMF.1.1/ESC, the evaluator shall conform that the
		management function is provided by the TOE. The evaluator shall also conform that the TSS details, for
		each supported management interface, which specific functions are available at that interface.</TSS>
		<Guidance>If "Ability to enable/disable voice and video recordings for any registered VVoIP endpoint" is selected, the
		evaluator shall examine the guidance document to verify it describes how to enable or disable recordings
		of voice and video calls.
		</Guidance>
		<Tests><testlist>
		<test>(Conditional): If “Ability to enable/disable voice and video recordings for any registered VVoIP
		endpoint” is selected, the evaluator shall deploy a test environment with two or more registered VVoIP endpoints. The evaluator shall choose two endpoints and configure the TOE to disable enable voice/video
		recording between them. The evaluator shall place a call between the two selected endpoints, verify that
		the call is successfully established, then terminate the call and verify that a recording is generated. The
		evaluator shall then configure the TOE to disable voice/video recording between the same two endpoints,
		repeat the call, verify that the call is established, then terminate the call. The evaluator shall examine the
		location where the first recording was generated and verify that no new recording is generated.</test>
		<test>The evaluator shall deploy a test environment with two or more registered VVoIP endpoints. The
		evaluator shall choose two endpoints, place a call between them, and verify that the call is successfully
		established. While the call is active, the evaluator shall use the TSF to review active connections and verify
		that the VVoIP endpoints’ connections to the TOE are active. The evaluator shall discontinue the call and
		verify that the TSF no longer shows the VVoIP endpoints’ connections to the TOE as active.</test>
		<test> (Conditional): If “ability to configure the password policy” is selected, the evaluator shall observe
		what the password strength policy is configured to by default on the TOE and shall verify that it is enforced
		by defining several weak administrative passwords for a given administrator account that are
		appropriately rejected by the TSF. The evaluator shall then modify the TOE’s password policy in such a
		manner that at least one of these weak passwords would now be accepted by the policy. The evaluator
		shall repeat the attempted password changes and observe that the TSF correctly accepts or rejects the
		passwords based on the new policy. </test></testlist></Tests>
		</aactivity>
	</f-element>
	<audit-event>
	<audit-event-descr>Enabling/disabling VVoIP endpoint/device features</audit-event-descr>
	<audit-event-info>ID of Administrator attempting to enable/disable service or feature on ESC or on external registered device;</audit-event-info>
	<audit-event-info>IP address of device where enabling/disabling of services or features was initiated;</audit-event-info>
	<audit-event-info>The feature or service that was enabled/disabled.</audit-event-info>
	</audit-event>
	<audit-event>
	<audit-event-descr>Modification of TOE Call Detail Records (CDR)</audit-event-descr>
	<audit-event-info>ID of Administrator attempting to query or modify database;</audit-event-info>
	<audit-event-info>IP address of device where database query was initiated;</audit-event-info>
	<audit-event-info>The exact SQL command/instruction that was executed.</audit-event-info>
	</audit-event>
	</f-component>


	</section>
	<section title="Protection of the TSF (FPT)" id="man-fpt">
	<f-component name="Failure with Preservation of a Secure State" cc-id="fpt_fls.1" id="fpt-fls-1" iteration="ESC">
		<f-element id="fpt-fls-1-1">
		<title>The TSF shall preserve a secure state <h:b>through the following means: <selectables><selectable>audible alarm</selectable>
			<selectable>visual indicator</selectable>
			<selectable>reboot of the TOE</selectable>
			<selectable>shutdown of the TOE</selectable>
			<selectable><assignable>other methods</assignable></selectable></selectables></h:b>
			when the following types of failures occur: [<h:i>failure
of self-tests defined in FPT_TST_EXT.1, failure of </h:i><assignable>hardware
components that affect the proper functioning of the TOE</assignable>].
			</title>
			<aactivity>
			<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it describes the TOE failures that can occur and the
			TOE’s response to these failures. The evaluator shall also examine the TSS to verify that it provides
			sufficient detail to justify how the TOE’s responses to these failures preserves a secure state.
			</TSS>
			<Guidance>The evaluator shall examine the guidance documentation and ensure that if the TOE’s failure handling
			behavior is configurable, any instructions for doing so are provided. The evaluator shall also examine the
			guidance documentation to verify that it identifies the potential failures that can occur and the TOE’s
			response to them so that the reader is aware of when the TSF has failed to a secure state.</Guidance>
			<Tests>The evaluator shall perform the EAs for FPT_TST_EXT.1 as defined in the NDcPP SD. For each self-test
			failure, the evaluator shall verify that the observed TOE behavior is consistent with the failure state
			defined in the TSS for this SFR. If this functionality is configurable, the evaluator shall reconfigure the TOE
			to each possible response to a self-test failure and re-execute the testing as many times as is necessary to
			demonstrate that the configured behavior is observed in each case.</Tests></aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event/>
	</f-component>
	</section>


	<section title="Trusted Path/Channels (FTP)" id="man-ftp">
	<f-component name="Inter-TSF Trusted Channel (ESC Communications)" cc-id="ftp_itc.1" id="ftp-itc.1-esc" iteration="ESC">
		<f-element id="ftp-itc-1e1"> 
		<title>The TSF shall <h:b>be capable of using TLS and <selectables><selectable>DTLS</selectable><selectable>IPsec</selectable><selectable>no other protocols</selectable></selectables> to</h:b> provide a communication channel between itself and another trusted IT product <h:b>supporting the following capabilities: VVoIP endpoints (for protection of signaling protocols), VVoIP endpoints (for protection of voice/video/media content), other ESC devices (for SIP trunking), <selectables><selectable>VVoIP conferencing system</selectable><selectable>no other capabilities</selectable></selectables></h:b> that is logically distinct from other communication channels and provides assured identification of its end points and protection of the channel data from modification or disclosure.</title>
		</f-element>
		<f-element id="ftp-itc-1e2-esc">
		<title>The TSF shall permit [<h:i>the TSF, another trusted IT product</h:i>] to initiate communication via the trusted channel.</title>
		</f-element> 
		<f-element id="ftp-itc-1e3-esc">
		<title>The TSF shall initiate communication via the trusted channel for <assignable>list of functions for which a trusted channel is required</assignable>.</title>
		<aactivity>
		<TSS>The evaluator shall perform the TSS evaluation activities specified in the NDcPP SD for FTP_ITC.1 for the
		communications interfaces and protocols specified in this iteration of the requirement.
		</TSS>
		<Guidance>The evaluator shall perform the AGD evaluation activities specified in the NDcPP SD for FTP_ITC.1 for the
		communications interfaces and protocols specified in this iteration of the requirement.</Guidance>
		<Tests>In addition to the assurance activities specified in the NDcPP SD for FTP_ITC.1, the evaluator shall perform
		the following tests:<testlist>
		<test>For each combination of signaling protocol (SIP, H.323), method of securing that protocol (IPsec,
		TLS), and method of securing transmitted media (SRTP, DTLS), the evaluator shall configure the TOE to
		use the selected protocols through a trunk to a remote ESC. The evaluator shall register a VVoIP endpoint
		to the TOE and a second VVoIP endpoint to the remote ESC. The evaluator shall place a packet sniffer on
		the network and capture traffic from the TOE to the local VVoIP endpoint and the remote ESC. The
		evaluator shall then place a call from one VVoIP endpoint to the other. The evaluator shall verify that the
		TOE’s audit trail shows that the local VVoIP endpoint was configured as a client using the configured
		protocol, that the traffic between the local VVoIP endpoint and the TOE is unintelligible, and that the
		traffic between the TOE and the remote ESC is protected for both signaling and media communications
		using the configured methods of securing them.<h:p>The evaluator shall repeat this test as many times as is necessary to demonstrate that each combination
		of securing the signaling protocol communications, securing the media protocol communications, and
		securing the SIP trunk from the TOE to the remote ESC can be used as claimed. Note that in any case
		where this results in double encryption of the traffic (e.g. SRTP-protected media tunneled through IPsec
		over a SIP trunk), the evaluator shall conduct the test with the outer layer enabled and then disabled in
		order to verify that both methods of protection are being used.</h:p></test>
		<test>(conditional): If ‘VVoIP conferencing system’ is selected, the evaluator shall repeat test 1
		(depending on the protocols the TOE claims to support) in an environment where the TOE is being used
		to establish a conference call between three or more registered VVoIP endpoints. In both cases, the
		evaluator shall verify that all SIP and SRTP traffic is encrypted.</test>
		</testlist></Tests></aactivity>
		</f-element> 
		<audit-event/>
	</f-component>
	</section>
	</man-sfrs>  <!-- SFRs -->

    <opt-sfrs>
	</opt-sfrs>		

	<obj-sfrs>
	</obj-sfrs>

    <impl-dep-sfrs>
	<section title="Auditable Events for Implementation-Dependent SFRs">
    		<audit-table id="at-impl-dep" table="impl-dep"/>
    	</section>
	
		<section title="Protection of the TSF (FPT)" id="imp-fpt">
		<f-component name="Trusted Update (VVoIP Endpoints)" cc-id="fpt_tud_ext.1" id="fpt-tud-ext-1-vvoip" iteration="VVoIP">
			<f-element id="fpt-tud-ext-1e1-vvoip">
			<title>The TSF shall provide Security Administrators the ability to query the
			currently executing version of the <h:b>registered VVoIP endpoint</h:b>
			firmware/software as well as the most recently installed version of the
			<h:b>registered VVoIP endpoint</h:b> firmware/software.</title>
			</f-element>
			<f-element id="fpt-tud-ext-1e2-vvoip">
			<title>The TSF shall provide Security Administrators the ability to manually
			initiate updates to <h:b>registered VVoIP endpoint</h:b> firmware/software and no
			other update mechanism.</title>
			</f-element>
			<f-element id="fpt-tud-ext-1e3-vvoip">
			<title>The TSF shall provide means to authenticate firmware/software updates
			to the <h:b>registered VVoIP endpoint</h:b> using a <selectables><selectable>X.509 certificate</selectable><selectable>digital signature </selectable><selectable>published hash</selectable></selectables> prior to installing those
			updates.</title>
			<note role="applications">
			<h:i><h:p>The TOE may either validate the update prior to storing it for delivery to
			registered VVoIP endpoints or it may provide the means to validate the
			update to the VVoIP endpoint itself by preserving the manufacturer’s
			integrity/authenticity mechanism and including that information in the update. In other words, either the TSF itself validates the update or it
			facilitates the ability of the VVoIP endpoint to do this by providing all
			information necessary to validate the update to the client. </h:p><h:p>It is typical behavior for ESCs to push software updates to registered
			VVoIP endpoint devices. However, many VVoIP endpoints have the ability
			to receive software updates from either an ESC or third-party update
			server. This SFR addresses the case where it is the ESC’s responsibility for
			delivery of software updates to registered VVoIP endpoints. For those
			scenarios where the VVoIP endpoint gets its upload from a separate
			server, then the ESC is not responsible for assuring
			FPT_TUD_EXT.1/VVoIP.</h:p></h:i>
			</note>
			<aactivity>
			<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it describes the ability of the TOE to retrieve VVoIP
			endpoint software/firmware updates and the process by which VVoIP endpoints can register to the TOE
			and acquire these updates. The evaluator shall also examine the TSS to verify that it describes by which
			the authenticity and integrity of VVoIP endpoint software updates are assured and what role the TSF has
			in ensuring that updates are genuine.</TSS>
			<Guidance>The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to verify that it provides instructions on how to
			acquire and verify a VVoIP endpoint software/firmware update from the manufacturer. The evaluator
			shall also verify that the guidance includes instructions on how an ESC administrator can use the TOE to
			apply software/firmware updates to registered VVoIP endpoints.</Guidance>
			<Tests>The evaluator shall perform the following test:<testlist>
			<test>Prior to downloading software update from TOE to registered VVoIP-client, the evaluator shall
			check to ensure the current version of the registered client device can be appropriately obtained by means
			of the operation methods specified by the administrator guidance.
			</test><test>The evaluator shall check to ensure that VVoIP endpoint software/firmware updates are signed
			and/or hashed by the manufacturer based on what is specified in the ST.</test>
			<test>The evaluator shall check to ensure that only administrators of the TOE are permitted to initiate an update to a registered VVoIP endpoint.</test>
			<test>The evaluator shall check to ensure that software updates are correctly performed by verifying
			that the VVoIP endpoint is running the newly-obtained software version obtaining the newly updated
			software version of the VVoIP-client device once update has complete.
			<h:p>Note: In some cases the ESC will not receive an explicit message from the VVoIP endpoint stating that the
			software update executed successfully. In addition, some software updates will not take effect until a
			reboot of the VVoIP endpoint is initiated remotely by the ESC or manually/physically at the VVoIP endpoint
			device itself. In either scenario, the VVoIP endpoint itself will always indicate whether verification of the
			update has failed. Therefore, the tester can (or may have to) verify successful software download by
			querying the VVoIP endpoint device for new software/firmware version. The tester can also verify
			whether software update failed by querying the registered VVoIP endpoint for errors.
			</h:p><h:p>In most cases, failed software update messages will originate from the VVoIP endpoint and not the ESC.
			Any failed software update reported by the registered VVoIP endpoint should have the report forwarded
			to the TOE. However, as mentioned earlier, the registered VVoIP endpoint may not report successful
			software downloads an therefore no ‘successful download’ report should be expected to be forwarded to the ESC. If the VVoIP endpoint does report a ‘software download complete’ or just ‘complete’, then the
			TOE should receive a message indicating that the download was completed. When the VVoIP endpoint
			reboots, it is expected to report the new software/firmware version to the TOE so that the new version
			will be displayed in the OA&amp;M application.</h:p></test>
			<test>The evaluator shall check to ensure that the verification of software/firmware updates from the
			TOE to the VVoIP endpoint fails using unauthorized data or improperly signed updates. The evaluator shall
			also check those cases where hash verification mechanism and digital signature verification mechanism
			fail.
			<h:p>Note: this may require the evaluator to obtain a deliberately invalid software update from the device
			manufacturer or developer access to the TOE so that a stored update can be manipulated directly in a
			manner that will cause signature and/or hash verification to fail.</h:p></test>
			</testlist></Tests>
			</aactivity>
			</f-element>
			<audit-event table="impl-dep"/>
		</f-component>
		</section>


	</impl-dep-sfrs>
	<sel-sfrs>
		<section id="sec-sel-audit-table" title="Auditable Events for Selection-based SFRs">
           <audit-table id="at-sel-based" table="sel-based"/>
	</section>
	<section title="Security Audit (FAU)" id="sel-fau">
		<f-component name="Selective Audit" cc-id="fau_sel.1" id="fau-sel-1">
		<depends on-sel="fmt-smf-1-1-esc-select2"/>
		<f-element id="fau-sel-1e1">
		<title>The TSF shall be able to select the set of events to be audited from the set of all
auditable events based on the following attributes:<h:ol type="a">
		<h:li><selectables>
			<selectable>object identity</selectable>
			<selectable>user identity</selectable>
			<selectable>subject identity</selectable>
			<selectable>host identity</selectable>
			<selectable>event type</selectable></selectables></h:li>
		<h:li><assignable>list of additional attributes that audit selectivity is based
		upon</assignable></h:li></h:ol></title>
		<note role="application"><h:i>This requirement must be claimed when ‘Ability to specify the set of audited events’ is chosen in FMT_SMF.1.1/ESC.</h:i></note>
		<aactivity>
		<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it identifies the attributes by which the TOE can be
		configured to selectively enable or disable the generation of auditable events.</TSS>
		<Guidance>The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to verify that it provides a list of the attributes that
		can be used to selectively enable or disable the generation of auditable events as well as instructions for
		performing this operation.</Guidance>
		<Tests><h:p>Note that the following testing may be done in conjunction with other EAs since auditable events occur
		as a by-product of the TOE being used to perform other security functions.</h:p>
		<h:p>The evaluator shall perform TSF-mediated actions with all auditable events enabled and observe that
		these events are audited as expected. The evaluator shall then log on to the TOE and disable auditable
		events by each attribute defined in the ST. The evaluator shall then re-execute the same set of TSF-mediated actions as before and observe that audit logs are not generated for all auditable events that are
		administratively disabled.
		</h:p></Tests></aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event table="sel-based"/>
		</f-component>

		<f-component name="Protected Audit Trail Storage (Voice/Video Recording)" cc-id="fau_stg.2" id="fau-stg-2-vvr" iteration="VVR">
		<depends on="fau-vvr-ext-1-1-have"/>
		<f-element id="fau-stg-2e1-vvr">
		<title>The TSF shall protect the stored <h:b>voice and video recordings</h:b> from unauthorized
			<h:b>disclosure</h:b> and deletion <h:b>by encrypting voice and video recording data that is stored
			on the TOE using an encryption method specified in FCS_COP.1.</h:b></title></f-element>
		<f-element id="fau-stg-2e2-vvr">
		<title>The TSF shall be able to [<h:i>prevent</h:i>] unauthorized modifications to the stored <h:b>voice and video recordings</h:b>.</title>
		<note role="application"><h:i>This requirement must be claimed if ‘have’ is selected in FAU_VVR_EXT.1.1.</h:i></note>
		<aactivity>
		<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it describes the method by which locally-stored voice
		and video recordings are protected and that this method uses cryptographic mechanisms defined in
		FCS_COP.1.
		</TSS>
		<Guidance>If the TOE provides the ability to enable/disable encryption of locally stored voice and video recordings,
		the evaluator shall verify that the operational guidance provides instructions on how to enable encryption
		and directs the reader to ensure that this is enabled in the TOE’s evaluated configuration.</Guidance>
		<Tests>The evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist><test>The evaluator shall verify that the TSF provides no interface to access voice/video recording data
		stored on the TOE except for legitimate access from an authorized administrator through the Operations,
		Administration, and Management (OA&amp;M) interface.</test><test>Both B2B subscriber calls and voice/video conferencing calls may be stored on the TOE based on
		safeguards (i.e. secured or unsecured) for which they were recorded. The evaluator shall identify the
		location of stored voice and video records and verify that this data is stored in an encrypted format for all
		types of voice and video calls that can be processed by the TOE. If this functionality is configurable, the
		evaluator shall follow the operational guidance to enable encryption prior to generating any voice/video
		recordings. </test></testlist></Tests></aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event table="sel-based"/>
		</f-component>

		<f-component name="Generation of Voice and Video Recordings" cc-id="fau_vvr_ext.2" id="fau-vvr-ext-2">
		<comp-lev> requires the TSF to store uniquely identified voice and video call recordings in a certain format and when certain conditions are met</comp-lev>
		<management>The following actions could be considered for the management functions in FMT:<h:ul><h:li>Ability to specify criteria for retention of voice and video recordings</h:li></h:ul></management>
		<audit>The following actions should be auditable if FAU_GEN Security Audit Data Generation is included in
the PP/ST:<h:ul><h:li>Voice/video recordings of completed calls</h:li></h:ul></audit>
		<dependencies>FAU_VVR_EXT.1 Recording Voice and Video Call Data</dependencies>
		<depends on="fau-vvr-ext-1-1-have"/>
		<f-element id="fau_vvr-ext-2e1">
		<title>The TSF shall provide the ability to retain voice and video recordings based on <assignable>administrator-specified criteria</assignable></title></f-element>
		<f-element id="fau_vvr-ext-2e2">
		<title>The TSF shall store voice and video recordings as <assignable>supported file
		format</assignable> data.</title>
		</f-element>
		<f-element id="fau_vvr-ext-2e3">
		<title>The TSF shall uniquely identify individual voice/video recordings using the following method: <assignable>unique identifying data</assignable>.</title>
		<note role="application"><h:i>This requirement must be claimed if ‘have’ is selected in FAU_VVR_EXT.1.1</h:i></note>
		<aactivity>
		<TSS>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it describes the conditions that can be set for the
		retention of voice/video recordings (all calls to/from a specific endpoint are recorded by administrator
		control, user manually specifies a call to be recorded at the start of the call session, etc.) and that these
		are consistent with what is specified in FAU_VVR_EXT.2.1. The evaluator shall also ensure that the TSS
		describes how voice/video recordings are retained, both in terms of the supported audio/video formats
		and how each recording is uniquely identified for future access.</TSS>
		<Guidance>The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to ensure that it describes how retention for
		voice/video recordings can be enabled and disabled, how stored records are encoded, and how they are
		uniquely identified.</Guidance>
		<Tests><h:p>The evaluator shall disable all mechanisms for voice/video recording. The evaluator shall then place a
		call that is mediated by the TSF and observe that no recording is generated after the call is completed.
		The evaluator shall then configure the TSF to enable recording, repeat the call, and ensure that a
		recording is generated in the required format after the call is completed. The evaluator shall then repeat
		this process and observe that a second recording is generated, and that the two recordings can be
		distinguished from one another using unique identifying information. The evaluator shall then disable
		recording, repeat the call, and observe that a recording is not generated.
		</h:p><h:p>If the TSF supports multiple mechanisms for enabling the recording of voice/video data, the evaluator
		shall repeat this test for each supported mechanism to ensure that voice/video recordings are only
		generated when that mechanism is active.</h:p></Tests></aactivity>
		</f-element>
		<audit-event>
		<audit-event-descr>Voice/video recordings of completed calls</audit-event-descr>
		<audit-event-info>Unique identifying data specified in FAU_VVR_EXT.2.3.</audit-event-info> </audit-event>
		</f-component>
	</section>
	</sel-sfrs>
    </sec:Security_Requirements> <!-- Security Requirements  -->

<appendix title="Inherently Satisfied Requirements" id="satisfiedreqs"> 
		<h:p>This appendix lists requirements that should be considered satisfied by products successfully evaluated
		against this PP. However, these requirements are not featured explicitly as SFRs and should not be
		included in the ST. They are not included as standalone SFRs because it would increase the time, cost, and
		complexity of evaluation. This approach is permitted by <xref g="CC"/> Part 1, 8.2 Dependencies between
		components.</h:p><h:p/>This information benefits systems engineering activities which call for inclusion of particular security
		controls. Evaluation against the PP-Module provides evidence that these controls are present and have
		been evaluated.
		<table xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
			<tr class="header">
				<td>Requirement</td>
				<td>Rationale for Satisfaction</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><b>FIA_UID.1 – Timing of Identification</b></td>
				<td>FIA_UAU.2 (which is iterated in this PP-Module as
					FIA_UAU.2/TC and FIA_UAU.2/VVoIP) has a dependency
					on FIA_UID.1 because authentication of an external entity
					requires that entity to first identify itself so that its identity
					can be validated by the authentication process.
					This SFR has not been defined in this PP-Module because
					in both iterations of FIA_UAU.2, the entity being
					authenticated is a trusted IT product in the TOE’s
					operational environment that communicates with the TSF
					over a channel specified in FTP_ITC.1/ESC. FTP_ITC.1/ESC
					explicitly states that the channel itself provides ‘assured
					identification of its end points’ which implies that these
					entities are identified prior to the authentication behavior
					required by the iterations of FIA_UAU.2.
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><b>FMT_MSA.3 – Static Attribute Initialization</b></td>
				<td><h:p>FDP_IFF.1 has a dependency on FMT_MSA.3 to define the
				default security posture of security attributes for the
				purpose of information flow control enforcement. This SFR
				has not been defined by this PP-Module because the
				enforcement of FDP_IFF.1 is not dependent on the initial
				state of security attributes. For example, FDP_IFF.1.2
				requires the TSF to determine if a communication attempt
				is valid before authorizing it. This is true regardless of
				whether the default value of security attributes associated
				with the connection attempt are permissive or restrictive;
				there is no difference in how the TSF determines “validity”
				in this case.</h:p><h:p>The default values of security attributes do not cause the
				information flow control policy to behave differently for
				those rules that must always be enforced by the TSF. The
				ST author has the ability to define additional default-allow
				or default-deny rules through the assignments in FDP_IFF.1.4 and 1.5. The ability to specify this behavior in
				the policy itself implies a default security posture of the
				relevant security attributes that does not need to be
				explicitly re-stated in a separate SFR.</h:p></td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</appendix>



	

	<!-- Entropy documentation -->
	<appendix title="Entropy Documentation and Assessment" id="entropyappendix"> 
		<h:p>
			The TOE does not require any additional supplementary information to describe its entropy source(s)
beyond the requirements outlined in the Base-PP. As with other Base-PP requirements, the only additional
requirement is that the entropy documentation also applies to the specific ESC capabilities of the TOE that
require random data, in addition to any functionality required by the Base-PP. 
		</h:p>
		
	</appendix>

	

	<!-- Abbreviations appendix is auto generated here -->
	
	<!-- Bibliography is auto generated here with CC and CEM docs. If you want other docs -->
	<!-- included, add them here. -->
	<bibliography>
      <entry id="bibCESG">
        <tag>CESG</tag>
        <description>CESG - <h:a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/end-user-devices-security-guidance"> End
            User Devices Security and Configuration Guidance</h:a></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibCSA">
        <tag>CSA</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/groups/SMA/ispab/documents/csa_87.txt">Computer Security Act
            of 1987</h:a>, H.R. 145, June 11, 1987. </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibOMB">
        <tag>OMB</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/omb/memoranda/fy2006/m06-19.pdf">Reporting Incidents Involving Personally Identifiable Information and Incorporating the
            Cost for Security in Agency Information Technology Investments</h:a>, OMB M-06-19, July
          12, 2006. </description>
      </entry>
	  <entry id="bibndcpp3">
			<tag>NDcPP</tag>
			<description>NDcPP  - <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/protectionprofiles/482">Collaborative Protection Profile for Network Devices, Version 3.0e, December 06, 2023</h:a></description>
			
		</entry>
		<entry id="NIST-SP-800-88">
		<tag>NIST SP 800-88</tag>
		<description>NIST-SP-800-88  - <h:a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/sp/800/88/r1/final">Guidelines for Media Sanitization, Revision 1, December 2014</h:a></description>
		</entry>
	</bibliography>

</Module>
